AI has learned code.
>> And if you don't realize that you could
just go to Claude and learn this stuff,
then you're not somebody I'm going to
invest in.
>> This is what this Claude code thing is.
There is zero time for The AI
model will be writing 90 90% of the
lines of code.
>> This computer can perform all these
things that you're instructing it to do
and doing it so easily. It's
>> like, hey, I need to raise some money so
I can go out and get a developer. Not
anymore. Not anymore.
There's only one skill that you need to
learn in 2026 because this one skill
will literally determine if you will be
successful in the future or and I'm very
sorry to say this, we always very direct
on this channel, if you will be
redundant and replaced by AI because the
future will look very very different
than the one we have now. And to be
frank, the current school system and
work environment is by no means
preparing people for what's to come in
the future. You will not be valued for
the work that you do. You're going to be
valued for how good you are at
instructing AI and doing stuff for you.
And it doesn't matter what industry
you're in. Big parts of it can be
automated if you know the right tools.
But lucky for you, you found this full
free course. Most guides on YouTube show
basic chat GBT or maybe Claude co-work.
But this is not one of those guides.
This is the full course for the only
tool you need to know how to use, which
is Claude Code. It's the tool that
everyone that actually understands AI
are using. And if you learn it, then
there's nothing that you can't automate,
nothing that you can't build. If you
don't know me, my name is Albert and I
didn't start technical. I didn't even go
to university. However, I still managed
to build something as technical as a
full software to over a million dollars
at the age of 23. VI coding with the
tool that I'm about to show you, the
tool that this entire course is about.
And it's not because I'm some genius.
I'm pretty average. It's because I
learned the right tools and how to use
them effectively. In this course, I'll
show you how to set it up the right way
and how to build anything from websites
that you can sell for a couple of
hundred bucks to full autonomous AI
systems that automate entire businesses.
And these AI systems can go from 10K to
multiple six figures. You are not going
to want to miss this one. Let's not
waste any more time. Let's get into it.
Claude Code can outdo this. Claude Code
is replacing my entire team. I just
built this with Claude Code and you
think, "Okay, let me check this out."
So, you open it up and it looks like
this. It looks scary when you just open
it up. By the end of this video, this
screen is going to feel like the most
powerful AI tool that you have ever
used. This is the full Claude Code
beginner's course. Let's get into it,
shall we? And this is probably you right
now. It's at least most people. Right
now most people are sitting in chat
activity or in cloud in the browser and
they're copy pasting things and asking
questions. They are trying to explain
their problems to the AI and every time
they create a new session some of that
information that they gave it is now
lost. So they have to reexlain things
over and over and over again about
themselves and their problem. And that
is where claude code comes in. The main
difference between claude in your
browser and then claude code is that
claude code lives right on your
computer. And I get it, it looks scary
in a terminal, but later in this course,
I'll show you how to set it up the right
way. What is the difference from claw in
your browser and then cloud code on your
computer? The main difference is that
with claude in your browser, you have to
paste in your project where if you have
a project on your computer, cloud code
can read all of that. It can find the
exact things, the exact context it needs
in order to solve problems. On top of
that, when you get a response from
tragicity or from claude, it tells you
what to do. Claude code can go in and it
can write the files for you. It can even
run code for you. So, it can test
itself. It if it makes a change to a
project, it can go in and test that
change itself and create a loop of
improvements. And when you learn how to
use cloud code the right way, which
we're going to take a look at later in
this course, you can also make Claude
code better as you use it and teach it
how to improve itself when it makes
mistakes. The way we can do this is with
Claude codes strongest feature in my
opinion, which is the Claude skills. The
skills allows you to build in rules
inside of Claude code that allows it to
behave or do something in a specific
way. If you are using claude code to
answer your emails, for example, you can
give it a claude skill that explains
exactly how you respond and you can
basically tune it to sound exactly like
you with a skill. Claude code is
something that I'd tell absolutely
everyone to learn because it's really
where things are heading right now. If
you've been in the AI space, then just
the past months, you've seen how much AI
has been exploding and how much better
it's getting every few months. Cloud
code is the way to give your AI as much
access, as much power as possible. So
you can make it do exactly what you want
because the terminal and living on your
computer is by far much better and much
more powerful the AI than being in your
browser in your terminal and on your
computer. It can run commands, it can
run code, it can build code, it can do
anything. And because of this and
because how much stronger claude code is
than regular claude, the gap between
people learning how to use this on their
computer and then just people using it
in the browser and the people learning
how to fully use AI are also the people
going to be able to take advantage of it
and be rewarded for it. And if you
really master plot code, then you can
set it up so it runs at all times. It
builds out things for you even when you
sleep. You have your own employees. And
this beginner course is designed to show
you exactly how to get started the best
way for just that. Let's get it set up,
shall we? The first thing you need, if
you haven't downloaded it already, is
something called NodeJS.
So, just search for NodeJS download and
then find this first one, nodejs.org,
and then download the right version for
your computer just by clicking Mac OS
installer right here and downloading it
to your computer because this allows you
to install cloud code directly with a
command. So just click the Mac installer
and download it directly to your
computer and install it just like that.
Now you want to install what's called a
code editor. And a code editor is
basically a place where your cla code
can live and also where you can see and
you can edit code. The best code editor
to use in my opinion is Visual Studio
Code. So you can just search for Visual
Studio Code download. That's going to
take you to this page right here and
then download it for your computer. When
you have it downloaded, then you can
open Visual Studio Code and it's going
to take you to this page right here
where we can open a project. Go to your
desktop or wherever you want to place a
project. Create a new folder and call
this something just to learn it. We'll
call it starter. Then you can go back
into Visual Studio Code. You can click
open. Then you can open the folder
starter that we just created
and click yes, I trust the authors.
There we go. I can click on this little
X right here to close the welcome page.
And now we have a code editor. And like
I explained before, a code editor is
basically just a place where you can
manage and edit code. And it's a really
good idea to run Claude Code from inside
of a code editor because that makes it
easier to see what Claude Code actually
does. The next thing we want to do is
that we want to open the terminal. And
on Mac, you can go up in the top, click
terminal, and click new terminal just
like this. If you want Windows, then you
can find the the Visual Studio Code
terminal command. If you click control
shift L and then this right here, then
it also opens the terminal. When you
have the terminal open, then go back to
your browser and search for Claude Code
install. And then click on this quick
start guide right here. When you scroll
down, you're going to find the
installation link. Just use the one
that's right for your computer. So, I'm
going to copy the Mac one. And I'm going
to insert this into my terminal. and
then hit enter. What this will do is
that this will download claude code to
our computer. You can see it says
setting up cloud code. Claude code
installed successfully. Installation
complete. Now in your terminal you can
write exactly like this clear. What this
does is that this clears the terminal
and then hit enter. After you've
installed it you can just write clawed
and this going to open the clawed
onboarding. We can choose what kind of
mode we want. I definitely want to
choose dark mode. And the way you move
around is that you use the arrow keys up
and down. And then when you want to
choose the option, then you just hit
enter. Now you have three options for
how you want to pay for Claude Code. If
you head over to Claude AI, if you don't
have it already, then set up account and
you go inside of view all plans, you can
see the plans that Claude Code have.
Right now, I am on the max plan because
I'm using Claude Code a lot. The best
place to start for you is probably with
the pro pro plan. It's $20 a month and
you can see this allows you to have
clawed code as well. You'll probably run
into some limit issues if you're using
claude code a lot, but start on the pro
plan and then later you can decide if
you want to upgrade. You can also use
the anthropic API key directly, but this
will cost you a lot more than just
getting a subscription inside of
claude.ai. Choose the plan that you want
and go through that flow of setting up
your account with your subscription.
After you've done that, you can go back
inside of Claude. You can choose claude
account with subscription. Hit enter and
this is going to open it up in your
browser where you can click authorize
and authorize your account. When you go
back into cloud, you can see it says
login successful. You can hit enter and
then hit enter again and then click yes.
Use recommended settings. Hit enter. And
there we go. Now we have claw code
successfully installed on our computer.
This right window on the right right
here also says build with AI agent, but
that's the native AI agent inside of
Visual Studio Code. We don't need that.
So, I'm just going to close that down.
We want to use clawed code. The way that
you navigate around is that you use
slash commands. So, if I write slash and
then click help, for example, I can see
all of the commands that I can use. I
can use the arrow keys to go from
general to commands and I can see all of
the commands that I can use. And there's
a lot of commands inside of cloud code.
If I want to get out of that view, I can
just click escape like I just did. And
that takes us back to the main page. If
I write /mod, that's one of the
commands. I can set the model that plot
code is using. You can see right now
it's on default and and it's using opus
4.6. If I wanted to, I can also choose
set, which is a lighter model. It's
cheaper. or I can use Hiker, which is
the fastest, but also a not as smart as
Opus. So, let's use Opus. What we can
also do if I use the arrow keys is down
at the bottom, you can see it says
medium effort. So, I can choose if I
want low effort, medium effort, or high
effort. And what this does is that this
basically determines for how long Claude
is thinking. For now, we're going to set
it to medium effort like it was by
default. And hit enter. If we any time,
you can see now we see some commands. If
you want to have a fresh workspace, then
you can just write slash clear. And this
basically just clears the entire
workspace and starts a new session. The
way cloud code works, just like you
would start a new conversation inside of
chat GBT, is that I can write, "Hi,
can you hear me?" And every time I do
this, it starts a new session. You can
see it says, "Yes, I can hear you. How
can I help?" I can start as many
sessions that I want inside of Claw Code
that can work in the same time. The way
I do that is that I can click this
little plus right here. And now you can
see it starts a new terminal right below
the the current one that we have. I can
then write Claude once again. And now
it's starting a new session. Do you know
my name?
And you can see it knows my name. And
now we have two different conversations.
If I want it in one view, I can do
what's called splitting the terminal.
And I do that by clicking this little
icon right here. And I basically do the
same as we just did. It's just in the
same view. So I can write cla again.
Then I can write hi. And now you can see
we have three different cloud sessions
running at once. That's one of the ways
that you can be very very productive
with claude code. You can run a lot of
sessions at once doing different things
to really boost your productivity. If I
wanted to stop a session, I can just
click on this little trash icon right
here, and this closes the terminal. So,
let me write clear. This basically
resets both sessions. If I write resume
now, I can see the previous
conversations that I had. You can see,
do you know my name? Hi. Hi. Can you
hear me? And if I wanted to go back to
one of those sessions, I can just hit
enter. And now we're back to the
session. Let me delete this so we only
have one to give you a better overview.
Right. Clear. And now we have a clear
conversation.
Okay, let's start building something so
you can see the power of claw code. What
I'll do is that I'll use this tool.
I want to build a website for my AI
agency that's called shiny.ai.
I want you to add a lot of animations. I
want just to build it with NextJS and I
want it to be really modern and really
clean and really futuristic with a lot
of different animations and good
copyrightiting that is high converting.
What this tool does is that this
basically takes my voice and then it
creates a really good prompt out of it.
So when I hit enter now, you can see it
took my voice, it created a full prompt
that's going to get us a way better
output. It says you are a senior
fullstack web developer with 8 years of
expertise in XJS. M web design. So it
gives it the role. It also gives out the
exact instructions to what I wanted to
say and then it explains how to format
it its response. And then it says,
"Please take your time with this. Thank
you for your help." Now it's going to
start building out this project for us.
Claude Code is now asking if it should
build out mockups for us. We don't want
that. So for now, I'm just going to say,
"No, just build it out for us, please.
Thank you." And there we go. Now Claude
Code will build out this entire website
for us. Sometimes it will request
approvals like this like if it can run
this command. So what we'll do is that
we will use our arrow keys go down to
yes and don't ask again and then hit
enter and then hit enter because cloud
code needs to install all of the things
that it needs. Same for this command. So
I'm just going to accept these things
that it asks for and then I'm going to
let it build out this website and this
is probably going to take around 5
minutes. There we go. This took about 5
minutes and now it says it is ready to
run it. It says npm rundev and then open
localhost. What does that mean? Well,
let me show you. You in a new terminal
click this little plus and that's
usually how you run whatever it is that
you have built. You have some command
that basically runs the project. And for
now it's npm rundev. So I'm going to
paste that in from Claude's instruction.
Hit enter. And now you can see starting
up our website on localhost 3000. So
what I'll do now is that I'll copy this
little URL right here. Write in
localhost 3000. Copy that in. Hit enter.
And now it's going to show our website.
Just like that. We built AI systems that
actually ship. AI moves the needle. Look
at this cool website that we just built
in 5 minutes. I hope you see the power
of what Claude Code can build in a very
short amount of time and think about the
possibilities. You can go out and sell
websites, apps, automations, automate
entire systems with Claude Code and sell
that to business owners. If you want the
quickest way to learn how to do that and
go out and do it, then you should
definitely check out our community, the
1% in AI. Inside of here, we are right
now running the 30-day challenge where
you get this sheet and when you fill out
this sheet and get to 100%, then see
what it says right here. complete the
30-day challenge and get a full refund.
If you want to check that out, I'll left
the link right below this video. The
next thing I want to show you is if you
write clear now and then you write
exactly this in it, then hit enter. What
this will do is that this will
initialize a new what is called a
claude.md
file. So, hit enter right here. And what
this will do is that this will force
claw to read through our project now
because we have now built a project and
create what is called a claude.md file.
And a claude.md file is basically
instructions specifically for claude in
this project for how to behave that it
reads every single time it starts a new
session. And there we go. Now we have
created a claude md file. We can find
this in our project directory that is
called claude.md.
This file right here is basically just a
text file that includes instructions,
but this will be read every single time
Claude starts a new session, which gives
it context.
So, what you can do inside of this file
is that you can add a rule section, and
then you can write never update any code
without first asking me three clarifying
questions about what it is that we are
updating. So you can basically give CL
code specific instructions for how to
behave every single session. If I write
clear now and I then say please change
the color to a light green on my website
and hit enter. Now you can see it says
before I make any changes I need to ask
three clarifying questions as per the
project rules. So now we can answer
these three questions. Yes.
uh what you prefer.
Yes.
And by knowing how to use the clude MD
file, you can give specific rules to for
how it should behave every single time.
And that is one of the most powerful
things with CLA code compared to claude
in your browser. You can decide it to
respond exactly like you want to by
creating and updating this claude.md
file. And now if we go back to our
website, you can see now our website is
green instead. The next thing I want to
show you is claude skills. You've
probably heard about them before. Claude
skills are pretty similar to the
claude.md file. It's also what's called
a markdown file. A markdown file is
basically just a text document like we
have here. You can see this is not code.
This is just text and it includes
instructions just like the rules that we
just added. What Claude skills are is
just specific documents that Claude
sometimes calls. And we can also
manually call a skill. If I write slash
and then skills and hit enter, you can
see the skills I have. I have a vibe
security skill. I have a prompt
architect skill. I have a composure
skill. I have a copyrightiting skill. I
have all of these skills inside of my
claw code. If you want all of the skills
that I'm using, then you can check out
our free community, completely free to
join. There's 147,000 people inside of
here already. If you go inside of
classroom and then inside of AI learning
hub and scroll down until you find the
claw skills, there's a drive folder
right here that basically just includes
all of my claw skills. Let me hit escape
here and go back and show you what a
skill is and how to install it. If I go
inside of this Google Drive right here,
and you can see this front-end design
skill right here, and I click on the
skill.md,
you can see what this actually is. It's
just a text document with instructions
for how to design. It says right up here
at the top name, description, and what
it's used for. The rest of the skill is
just a detailed prompt for how the AI
should design. I really hope that you
guys are enjoying this course. I'm
trying to provide as much value
completely for free. It would mean the
world to me if you hit the subscribe
button. Doesn't cost you anything, but
it helps me out a ton. All right, let's
continue with the video. Let me show you
how to actually use a skill. If I write
slash and then front end design and I'll
show you how to install skills in just a
second. I just want to show you the
power of it. I will paste in a section
right below this that I want to give a
makeover. I want to give it a clean
animation that has something to do with
lead reactivation and engaging old leads
and conversations with those. I wanted
to create a detailed animation that
looks very professional for my website
in the hero section. This will write out
the entire prompt for us in a structured
manner and not this messy manner that I
just explained in. Then we can go and we
can copy this and we can basically just
include this. This is the section I want
to give a makeover
and then hit enter. Now we're using the
front end design skill which is used for
beautiful front end design. We're giving
a good prompt for what we want to
include and then we paste it in the
section that we want to change. when we
give it this skill, it's automatically
going to get this context inside of this
file. And that's the idea. That's the
reason that we use skills. We give it
the right context, the right
instructions for creating really nice
design. And now it's going to use this
information and give us a better result.
That's the entire reason that we use
claw skills. It's to give us the best
possible results. Cool. Now, it made a
bunch of changes. Let's see how the
animation actually looks.
You can see it created a really cool
looking animation going on in the
background with this front end design
skill. We can tip and tune this. But I
hope you see the point that you can use
the front end design skill to improve
how cloud code is sign stuff and you can
basically find a skill for whatever it
is that you're trying to create. Let me
show you how to install a cloud skill
cuz it's very easy. All we do is that we
find the skill that we want to install
like this front end design skill. Click
download and this will download it as a
zip file. Now double click on the zip
file to unzip it and then go inside of
plot code and run a new session.
Now drag this into plot code and then
write exactly this. Please research how
to install plot skills from
documentation and then install this
skill. It's that easy. And that's
another great thing about claude code is
that when you want to install something
99% of the time you can get cloud code
to install it for you or at least
instruct you in how to do it. Another
key difference from something like chat
GPT. ChatGpt would explain how you go in
and install it. Claude Code installs it
for you. Now you can see it's searching
up the documentation online. And now
it's going to install this claw skill.
And there we go. Now the claw skill is
installed. to check that you now have
this the skill installed. Click Ctrl C.
Then you basically go out of Claude
code. So what I want to do now is that I
want to restart Claude. And that's also
how you do that. You click Ctrl C. What
this will does that this will close
code. And then we just write Claude
again. That's going to open up a new
Claude instance. And now if you write,
you will now be able to see the front
end design skill. And it's that easy.
That's how you create skills. You can
literally just download this entire
folder and then get all of my skills in
literally like 1 minute just by taking
this claude skill and just say research
the claude documentation
and then install these skills. Now I
already have them installed so I don't
need to do that. Awesome. Now you have
installed cloud code, you have built
your first project and you understand
claude skills already. Now you
understand more than 80% of people and
you can really go down into a rabbit
hole here. You can do so much with claw
code. You should just start building.
That's the only way to get good with
these tools is to actually use them
absolutely every single day. You can
build automations. You can build
websites. You can build software. You
can build apps. Whatever it is that you
want to build, just start building.
Learn how to use the tools. Learn how to
prompt. I promise you it will be so
worth it.
A wise man once said that you have to
get good before you can get rich. What
do I mean with that? What you've
probably seen on Instagram and all the
other socials as well is people saying
go out, learn how to build websites, and
sell your first one for $10,000. And
while it is true that you can sell
websites for this much, is it realistic
that you're going to go out and close a
10K deal as your first one? Well,
probably not. And that is also what I
mentioned earlier when we talked about
expectations. It's probably not going to
go that way. Why is that? Well, there's
a couple of reasons. The first one is
that you have absolutely no trust. And
how do you build trust? Well, you need
testimonials and you need previous
experience. So, when you hop on a call
with someone that you actually know what
you're talking about, that you're
actually certain in yourself that, okay,
you can help this person get better
results. In this course, I'll show you
how to get both of those things. And
what I'll also show you is the next part
that you're lacking, which is skills.
For some reason, these days, people
think that you can just go out and learn
something in 5 minutes and all of a
sudden charge thousands of dollars for
it. I'm sorry, but that is not reality.
You've got to understand that what
people are paying you for is the time
and effort you've put in to gather
skills. Skills that this person that are
paying you doesn't have themselves. If
it was easy, the thing that you were
doing, the thing that you had learned,
then no one would pay you for it. So,
you have to do exactly what it is that
you're doing right now and watching this
video, you have to go out and you have
to learn. You have to build these skills
in order to get paid. And that's exactly
what I mean when I say you have to get
good before you get rich. And of course,
that's also the entire point of this
video is to get you to build those
skills. When I started my AI business,
it didn't take a week. It didn't take a
month. It didn't take two months. It
took four months before I closed my
first paying client for $400. And guess
what I did before that? I did not charge
$10,000 for a website. I actually did
free work in order to actually build
trust, to gain experience, and to gain
testimonials. And by doing the free
work, I also gained the skills that I
could later monetize and actually charge
for. So, if you're thinking right now,
okay, I'm going to go out, I'm going to
learn this, and then the next week I'm
going to sell a 10K website, leave this
video. This video is not for you.
Understand that you have to build the
skills before you can charge anything.
And understand that this takes months.
The way that I think about it is that
there's kind of like three different
levels to what you can be building when
you're just starting out. The first
level that I would recommend that you
start with is AI generated websites,
specifically with Cloud Code. It's
extremely good at building websites. And
let me show you something very, very
interesting. If I head over to Claude
and I ask how many small businesses
still don't have a website, while I then
drink my coffee, Claude is now going to
research the web and find out the
number. And now we can see that roughly
27 to 30% of businesses in 2026 have no
website. So roughly one in three small
businesses still don't have a website.
So if you learn that skill of building
websites, all of a sudden you can
provide services to that 30%. and that
30% does not have a website. You can
also build better websites and sell it
to the rest of the 70% if you provide
something that's better than what they
currently have. So I can write okay so
if it's 30% how many businesses in that
in let's say the US just to put a number
for how many potential businesses that
you could actually be working with. I'll
take another sip of the coffee while
Claude is researching. So in the US
there are 36 million small businesses
and 30% of that is then 10 million
businesses without a website and that is
in my opinion the best place to start.
Now you have millions of businesses that
you could service with your skills. They
don't know how to build websites with
something like code. They are not going
to learn it. They are focused on their
craft. So when you in this course is
going to learn how to build websites,
all of a sudden you can service all of
those businesses and provide a valuable
service. That is level one out of three.
The next thing we're going to take a
look at is the step up. Now you're not
only building websites, you're also
automating their business with
automations and agents. This requires
some more knowledge into integrations
and APIs, but don't worry, you're going
to be learning how to do that as well.
And I would say the final level is
building out full AI systems for
businesses that not only integrate into
what they already have, but also where
you are collecting all of the
automations that you have built from
level two and then maybe creating a
dashboard or somehow building it into a
full AI system. But of course, we don't
start at level three. We start at level
one, websites. And stay around because
later in the video, I'm going to show
you exactly how you build those out in
just a couple of minutes. If we do a
small plot search and we basically just
ask how many businesses in the US are
still missing a website, what we will
find is approximately 30% of US small
businesses don't have a website in 2026.
Right now there's approximately 36
million small businesses in the US,
which means that we have around 10
million businesses without a website.
And that's also why I previously showed
you these three levels of things that
you can build right off the bat where
website is level one. The reason for
that is that what this entire business
model is about is that you learn skills,
you learn how to do something well,
where businesses would rather pay you to
do it than do it and find out how to do
it themselves. And building websites is
one of those things that still have a
lot of perceived value. If people see a
very nice website, they think, "Okay,
that must have cost a lot." Even to this
day where AI is so good at building
websites, there's a lot of perceived
value in websites. And that is also why
it's what we're going to start off with
building. Here's an example of the
website that you're going to learn how
to build. And I'll even give you this
template right here. So, you can
actually build exact websites like this
from one prompt. You can see we have
this navbar right here that when we
scroll that becomes like a sticky nav
bar at the top. I really like this
design. The choice of colors, the choice
of fonts. It looks very, very
professional. And what you'll also be
learning in this next part of the module
is how to also make these websites
actually high converting because that's
one of the places where a lot of website
designers, they mess up. It's because
they create websites that might look
good, but they are not high converting.
You can see there's a very bright button
right here that you would want to click
on. And you also have a number right
here that you can call if you want to
call them straight away. You'll also
learn how to create these very, very
clean animations directly with code and
plot code. You can see this little
plumbing animations right here from the
pipe and this calendar animation right
here. All of these you'll learn how to
create. You'll learn how to prompt
claude to get a result that looks this
good. You'll also learn how to create
these type of animations which are kind
of like these cards where they stack on
top of each other which looks very
professional. Then you'll learn how to
split this into a dark mode that creates
like a very nice contrast. And at the
end you're going to have this form right
here and I'm going to show you how you
can hook this website up to any CRM that
you want. This is a very nice website
and usually web agencies can charge a
lot. If I create a new chat and I ask
Claude, "How much does web agencies
charge for a nicel looking website?" The
result will probably surprise you. Look
at this. Depends on a lot what nicel
looking means, but rough market ranges.
For a solo freelancer on a template
where it takes 1 to two weeks, you can
charge 1 to 3k. If it's a small
boutique, then it's 3 to 10k. If it's a
proper agency, it's 10 to 30k. If it's a
mid-tier agency, it's 30 to 80k. And if
it's a ward tier, like a big web agency
where they really spend a lot of the
time on the design, they can charge 80
to $250,000.
And if it's some of the very well-known
brands, they can charge $250,000.
And you can even see for my agency
recommend to $10,000 for websites. So
you can see how much you can actually
charge. And again, to set your
expectations, you're not going to go out
and close your first website to $10,000.
But what you might go out is close a
website for $500, which would still be a
massive win with users starting out. And
we can build all of this from inside of
Claw Code. I'm going to show you how to
build it. Of course, I have a skill that
creates these websites in literally just
like 5 minutes. I'll show you how you
hook this up to any CRM. So, the
information that is captured when people
click get an offer is actually being
sent to somewhere. And I'll show you how
to make your website responsive so it
looks good on both desktop and mobile.
And I'll also show you how you can host
and deploy a website for free up to a
certain amount of traffic. But usually,
if you're doing it for smaller
companies, the hosting would be free.
You're going to learn a lot in this next
part. So, let's get into it. To build
clean websites like this, you're going
to be using the build premium website
skill. And again, you can find all of my
claw skills inside of our completely
free community. Just go inside of
classroom, then learning hub, scroll
down until you find my claw skills right
here. I'll also leave a link to this
right below this video. This drive
folder includes all of my cloud skills
because after you've installed this
skill and you write slash build premium
website, you can see this skill builds a
premium animated marketing website with
reactivite and tailwind CSS for any
industry. Use when the user has to build
a website blah blah blah. So we're going
to use it and write /bu premium website.
I want to build a website for a
landscaping company. Let's just call it
cityscape. Then we hit enter because
what this skill will now do is that it's
going to force claw to ask follow-up
questions about exactly what side it is
that we want. So the colors, etc. There
we go. Now it's going to ask us what the
theme should be. I think a bold modern
theme looks good. The brand color
direction, urban slate, mos, forest,
rust, olive, brass. I think this dark
green one, moss green, could look pretty
cool. So let's go with that. Let's go
with design. Heartscaping lawn trees
lighting commercial for the services. I
think that's pretty good. And then I'm
going to ask it to build it in this
folder
that we are currently
in. I'm going to write submit answers.
And now it's going to build out the plan
for this website. You can see it's
reading all these files from inside of
the skill that it uses as a reference
for how it should design this. Building
this out can take a couple of minutes.
And there we go. That took 8 minutes and
41 seconds. And now you can see site is
live at localhost 5173.
So, I'm going to copy this. Then I'm
going to go into our browser, paste this
in, hit enter, and there we go. Now we
have it. Cityscape, home, services,
approach, process, contact. Then we have
request a quote right up here. Landscape
architecture for the city. We design,
build, and maintain. And now we have a
clean website in literally just 8
minutes. That's based on this template.
And you can see we have this animation
right here with these stock images,
which looks extremely good. We're
missing one right here. So we need to
fix that. Every discipline under one
roof from a single tree prun to halfacre
estate planted from scratch. This looks
extremely good. Request a quote. When
they click on this, it scrolls to this
section right here where they can fill
in this information. They can even
attach photos if they want to. And then
they can send the inquiry. Absolutely
insane website. You can see this website
right here is built from the same
template that we used for the plumbing
company. I'm really happy with how this
site turned out. We can also right click
and click inspect and then turn it to
mobile right here. And then we can see,
okay, it also looks good on mobile,
which is also very important for
websites these days. Great. You learn
how to create insane looking websites.
And you can sell this for probably
around 500 bucks. But let me show you
how to also deploy it. You deploy it by
first going to GitHub. If you don't have
GitHub already, then create a profile.
Then click new. And I'm going to call
this cityscape right here. You're going
to set it to public because you don't
want to give everyone your code to your
website. And then you click create
repository. There we go. And now you can
take this URL right here and you can
pass it to claw code. And you can say
push this code for the website only to
this repo. Then you don't want to have
it in auto mode because it won't be able
to push to repo in auto mode. So you're
just going to set it like this. Hit
enter. And now cloud is going to push
all of this code into the cloud into
GitHub. And you can see it's first
checking. Hit enter. When you do this
the first time, it'll pop up with an
authentication where you have to
authenticate in order to do this. It'll
basically just open a window on your
GitHub where you just have to click
accept. But because I've done this
plenty of times, it already has a
connection. Now, it is creating a
commit. And you can see pushed code is
live at this GitHub UL right here. If we
then hit enter on the GitHub repo, then
we can see our code from this website.
and hosting it is actually extremely
easy when we have it on GitHub. I'm
going to use the platform that's called
visil.com which is a hosting platform.
Then if you don't have it already,
create a user. It's free. Go in the top
right corner, click add new, and then
project. And then you can paste in this
GitHub repo right here when you have
your GitHub account connected to your
VIL account. This makes it very very
easy because VIL can now see
automatically, okay, this is a V
project. It's called Cityscape. And all
we have to do is just click deploy once.
And there we go. Now you can see it's
being deployed. This should take usually
around something like 30 seconds before
the website is deployed. This actually
only took 9 seconds this time. You can
see it says congratulations, you've now
deployed a new project. We can then
click continue to dashboard. And here we
have our project. We actually already
have a domain that's given by VIL. If we
copy this domain right here and we open
it in a new tab, this is the domain that
we have been given. Then we actually
have a preview of what the site will
look like when it's live. And it's
actually live right now. We can go to
this website from anywhere. And you can
see it looks extremely good. Looks
exactly like it did on development. If
you wanted to add a domain, you would
come down here onto domains on the left
hand side. And you can see we have our
standard domain right here. You would
just click add existing. And here you
can add any domain that you want from
GoDaddy, from NameCheep, from
Cloudflare, it doesn't matter. It will
take you through the review process of
setting up the DNS. And when you have
done that, then you have deployed your
website to the web. If you wanted to
sell these kind of websites, I would
create five different templates and then
create a portfolio website where you
show these websites that you have built.
That makes it much easier for a
potential client to make a decision.
Okay, should I work with this company or
not? The great thing about this is that
when you have built up a portfolio and
when you have built a bunch of skills
like this, I'll show you later in this
course how you can create something and
then create your own skill so you can
replicate the process much much easier.
your work becomes almost automated.
Claude can do 95% of your product
delivery. And that's the entire point of
this business model. It's to build stuff
with Claude and then creating skills
from it to replicate the process and
making the service delivery so much
easier. All right, that is websites
complete. The next thing you're going to
learn is how do you actually automate
things? If a client comes to you and
says, "Well, I want my invoicing process
automated or I want my onboarding
process automated." How do you actually
go about doing that? How do you create
automations with claude code? Usually,
you would use a platform like make.com
or like nm. But with cloud code, there's
a much better way of doing it. Now, we
can use the platform that's called
trigger.dev. Trigger is an open- source
platform for building and hosting
automations. You can see that it's open
source right here. It has 15,000 GitHub
stars and we can see the entire codebase
right here. Why is it smart to use
trigger.dev over something like naden or
make? It's a very simple reason. The
reason is that trigger.dev is built with
code and cloud code is really good at
coding. We actually already have a skill
that's called trigger.dev. And this
skill is going to be very important when
we build out those workflows. So what
I'm going to do is that I'm going to
clear the session inside of claw code.
And let's build out a couple of
automations with trigger.dev so you can
see how it works. I'm going to write I
want to automate my invoicing process. I
want to be able to fill out a form with
a bit of information and then it should
build the invoice,
export as PDF
and then send via Gmail to the client.
Use two skills and you will have access
to both of these skills as well. First
one is the Composio skill. I want to use
Composio
for authentication. Skill two is
trigger.dev.
I want to build and host this with
I'm going to give it an ultraink. Put it
in plan mode. And let's build this out.
Remember what I showed you before with
the process of connecting claw directly
with your AI noteaker like Fathom via
the MCP. Right now, I explained what I
wanted, right? But if you're talking to
a client, I want this and this and this
automated. You can take that directly
that context directly from the call into
cloud code and then you don't even have
to explain it like I did here. What
fields should the invoicing form capture
it should capture it all. So business
information, contact information, line
items,
tax and discounts,
everything that we usually
have on an invoice. It should create its
own invoicing number and it should take
the date automatically. Then we hit
enter and there we go. It's now going to
plan out the process of automating this
process of creating invoices. For how we
trigger the automation, I think we
should use a simple web form from
Nex.js. So I'm going to choose simple
web form and hit enter. For the
environmental value, it's very important
that they're not hardcoded, but in av
file, please. Let's use React for the
PDF. And for the invoice number, let's
do it date based. And then we hit enter.
If you know how to build with cloud
code, it almost doesn't matter what it
is that you're building. If you know the
process of first planning it out, making
sure that you actually give it the right
context so it knows exactly what you
want, then the opportunity is literally
endless. You can build basically
anything that you want. If you know the
actual formatting and the method of
building stuff here, it's asking about
the invoice counter. I think it's a bit
overkill to set up the invoice counter
in a database. So, I'm just going to say
let's skip the invoice counter for now
and just do it date based the naming
for the invoicing. I think both
attaching the PDF and storing it in
Google Drive is going to be best. Who
writes the subject? Fix template with
placeholders. Let's actually do it AI
generated. So, the email is AI
generated. And then we hit enter. Now,
it's going to plan out exactly how we
can do this. And there we have it. We
have an entire plan for how we should
build this out. What's worth noticing is
that we are using Composio. If you don't
know what Composio is, it's a tool for
authentication. So, we can authenticate
to a bunch of different things very,
very easily. I made a full guide for
Composio on my channel. So, if you want
to, you can go and watch that later. And
then it's using trigger.dev for building
and hosting this automation. The great
thing about trigger.dev is that it's
open source. And when it's open source,
we can host this anywhere we want. The
easiest thing is probably just to host
it with trigger.dev and that's how they
make money as well. But if you wanted to
or if your client wants this on their
own servers, then you can literally just
build these workflows and host them
wherever you want. That's the power of
open source. So now we have a plan.
Let's take yes and use auto mode and
let's build out this automation. There
we go. Now we can see that it is built.
Let me open another terminal. The first
thing we do is that we need to fill out
this envir environmental file right
here. I'm going to click new file. Add
add a.in file. Copy this example over.
And then we need to fill out all of this
information. So the first thing we need
is a trigger secret key. If you don't
have it already, then make sure to
create a user on trigger and log in. I'm
going to create a new project. So in the
top left plan, I'm going to create new
project. I'm going to call this one
invoicing. And just click create. Now we
can head under API keys and then copy
this secret key right here. So we paste
that in where it says secret key. And
then we also need to go in and find the
project ref right here. Copy this one as
well. Now we need the Composio API key.
So we go to Composio and Composio is
basically what manages our
authentication. If you don't have a
Composio account then sign up for one.
It is free up to a certain amount of
tool calls. Copy the composure API key
and insert that as well. Now we need the
enthropy API key. This is used for the
AI generation of the email. So we're
going to platform.plot.com.
Go into API keys. Click create key. Call
this invoicing.
Click add. Copy this key. Paste that in
as well. We need the Google Drive folder
ID. We get that by going to drive. We
just create a new folder. I'm going to
call this invoices. If we click in on
that, we get this ID right here in in
the header. So, I'm going to copy this
one. Then, we write all of this
information, which is our business info.
So, let's just try and see if it works.
I'm going to write test street 1 2 3
building 4 the business phone number.
Just write in some random phone number.
Business logo URL. We can go to our
shiny website. We can copy this image
URL right here. That way we don't need
to host it, which is smart. Business
bank details. Let me just write a random
eban. Default currency USD. Default tax
rate zero. Default payment terms net 14.
Default due days. This looks good.
Awesome. Then we close down this
environmental file and we say great I
have filled out the invent file. What
now? or do we or
now run the one time compos your script.
It'll print out two or URLs Gmail drive.
You click through both and it waits
until each connection flips active. Let
me just create a new API key. Maybe it
was an old one that's already rotated.
I'm going to write try again. We still
had a bug. This is a new bug. So clude
can just fix that. There we go. Now you
can see it says Gmail oorthth URL. So
it's going to give us this URL right
here that I can copy and put into our
browser. And this is how Composio works.
This means that we don't have to set up
the Google credentials ourselves. We can
use Composio that just gives us this
link right here and then click continue.
And you can see now Composio is
connected to Gmail. I can now say done.
Come with all URLs please. So we can
connect. And for each service that we
connect, it's going to give us a new
URL. So now we have the Google Drive URL
right here. Paste that in once again.
Log in with our Google account. There we
go. And now you can see. Then open
localhost 3001 server is still not
running. So I'm going to ask please run
the dev server for me. And there we go.
Now the two servers are started both the
back end which is trigger.dev and our
front end. We can go to localhost 3001.
And now we have send an invoice
generates a PDF drafts with email with
claude and ships it via Gmail bar from
default currency USD tax 0% terms net 14
due in 14 days. So I can write the
client's name is let's do Albert testing
and let's do the company as let's just
call it my agent and the address we
maybe don't need to I can do like
King Street 420
line items we can do consulting services
one quantity price let's do 1,500 we
need another which is upfront fee let's
do one call that 500 currency money and
date currency we speed will be USD tax
rate zero
Discount type none. Discount value none.
Issue date, let's do that. The 18th due
date, we can just leave that. Payment
terms net 14. Any notes? No. And then we
can click generate and send. Of course,
we need an email right here. Let me just
write in my own email just as a test.
And then click generate and send. You
can see it says cute run ID and then
this run right here. Let's see if it
works. Let's ask CL now to check the
logs. Did my test work? You can see it
checked the logs and found a couple of
issues. So, let's let Claude fix those.
Keep doing runs and you can see Claude
fixed one issue. Let's try and check the
logs again. Ran into another bug. We'll
fix that. Try and submit once again.
Check now. And we just keep doing that
until cloud has fixed all of the bugs.
You can see Composer won't use ID this
depending on the tool. Submit again.
Let's do that. Generate and send now.
There we go. Finish. Success. Let's see
how it looks. If we go to my Gmail and
now hit a refresh, you can see we just
received an invoice from me. Hi Alba. I
hope things are going well at build my
agent. Please find attach invoice for
$2,000 dub by payment net terms of 14.
So let me know if you have any
questions, need anything from my end.
Thanks so much for continue trust and
working with China. It really means a
lot. And here we have an invoice that is
generated 100% by our workflow. It has
all of our information invoice number
like this and this and this. They had 14
payment details. Boom. If a company now
comes to you and say, "Well, we spent a
lot of time sending out invoices." You
know how to fix it. And we've just
successfully built a trigger. Workflow
without even being inside of a workflow
builder or anything. Claude did it all.
But let's say we want to deploy this,
right? Right now, it's running from our
computer. It's doing all of this from
our computer. We can then write, "Let's
deploy this to production on trigger
dev." Thank you. The way that
trigger.dev dev works in the cloud is
that you have these projects right here
and inside of here you have different
environments like right now I'm in
development but we want to be on
production so now you can see cloud is
deploying this it's pushing it into the
triggerdevcloud but we have to do is
just set the environmental values we do
that by going into environmental values
right here and then clicking add new
then making sure that we have it on
production right here a quick tip is
that you can go inside of environmental
value copy this then you can go back and
paste all of this in. We're just going
to show all of the environmental values
the right way. We can click save. And
there we go. All of the environmental
values has now been added. And there we
go. Plot has now pushed our task. You
can see our task inside of here. Now,
send invoice has now been added. We
don't have any activity yet because we
just pushed it to production, but we can
run it again if you want. So, let's test
it. Before we test it, we need to take
the API key from inside of production
cuz that's going to be a different
secret key. And we need to go in and
fill out this new information. So the
trigger secret key, change that to prod.
Same with the project reference right
here. That's actually the same. So we
don't need to do anything there. Let's
test it now by running npm rundev. I'm
going to write let's test it in
localhost 3000 first.
Form
I change the environmental values. Let's
try and test it now. So I'm going to
write elot testing 2. Going to send it
to my own email once again. going to
call it build my agent 2 and address we
don't want I'm just going to call it
testing for let's say 1 1500 USD blah
blah blah all of this we don't need
generate and send now you can see it
says sending cute run if you now go into
trigger.dev dev and to our task. You can
now see one run was just cued right
here. We can also see run is now being
executed. That's one of the good things
about trigger.dev as well is that all of
this dashboard right here where it's
executing all of the runs. We have a
very clean dashboard where we can see
what's going on. And now we can see
right here the run succeeded in 13
seconds. If we go to our invoice and
give it a refresh, we now have a new
invoice with this new information. And
our invoice generator is now deployed in
the cloud. So that is the back end,
right? The back end is now deployed on
trigger.dev. If we wanted to deploy the
front end as well, we can also do that.
We head to Vessel and then we write
great. Let's push the front end to Vel.
First GitHub though. We're going to go
to GitHub and just like we did before,
we're going to create a new repo. I'm
going to call it invoice front end. We
can choose an owner. We're going to
choose ourselves. We can click private
and then we can create the repository
just like this. Paste this into claw.
Hit enter. And now it's going to push
our front end. Our front end is this
page right here, right? The invoice
generator. It's going to push that. So
we have it online. The crazy thing about
this is that you don't have to remember,
okay, how exactly did Albert do this?
You just have to remember you can use
composio for authentication. Trigger.dev
for the actual automation. When you tell
that to claw, claw can figure out the
rest. There we go. It is now pushed. We
can now just like we did before go to
visil, click add new project, paste this
in, click deploy, choose next, and just
click deploy again. And that will deploy
our project to the web. There we go. It
is now deployed. We can click continue
to dashboard. Click on the domain right
here. And now you can see the invoice
generator is live on the web. The last
thing we need to do is just set the
environmental values. You do that by
going in environmental variables right
here. Click add environmental variables.
and just take the same one that we used
before. Paste that into the cell like
this. Click save. You're going to have
to redeploy. And now the invoice
generator is live on the web. What's
important to know is that right now we
have hooked our entropic API key up to
this invoice generator. It generates
this text right here with AI when it
sends the email. The issue with that is
that if someone got access to this
invoice generator, they could send maybe
a thousand emails which will burn a lot
of credits on Claude. So you want to add
some authentication. And you don't want
to just deploy it like this. And in the
next part of the course, I'm going to
show you exactly how you do that.
Because you're usually not only going to
give them one of these like automations.
Usually, when you automate something
within a business, you're automating
maybe 5, 10, 20 different processes that
adds up to a bunch of time. This is just
one of them. In the next part of the
course, I'm going to show you how you
can add authentication as well, so only
the actual company can access this. And
I'm going to show you how you can build
almost sort of a mini app with a bunch
of individual small tools like this one
where all of the automations are in one
place that you can then give to the
client which makes you look very very
professional and a collection of these
is something that you can charge 105
$20,000 for if you're doing it for big
companies. There we go. Deployment has
been created. If we go to it now you can
see it has all of our information from
before and now it will work from the
web. Throughout this course we've built
a lot of things using skills. For
example, the website that we created was
heavily carried by this build premium
website skill. This is probably one of
the most important parts about this
entire course. And the reason for that
is that one of the most important skills
that you want to learn if you want to do
this oneperson AI plot business is to
create a process. Spend a lot of time
building something out like this
invoicing for example, and then building
a skill so you can cut a lot of time if
you had to build it again. So, learning
how to build generic skills that builds
out a process exactly like how you want
it will save you a bunch of time in the
long run. And the way you want to do
this is that you want to use my skill
that's called create skill. This skill
is also inside of our drives. This one
right here called create skill which
instructs Claude in how to create a good
skill. I'm going to say nice, well done.
This was a success.
I want to
create a skill for creating simple
automations like this where I have some
kind of form
and that
is on nextjs that's what we used and the
back end is on trigger authentication if
possible should be on composio I want
you to take what you learned from this
session and add that information into a
skill so we can replicate it in in the
future.
Very important.
Use the create skill skill that you have
access to. The user should in the start
answer a couple of questions about what
it is that they want to build.
The skills should be generic for any
mini automation slashtools that they
want to build. So it shouldn't be
invoicing
specifically
in the skill include that
claude should research before building.
Then you want to hit it with an ultra
think. You want to hit it with plan
mode. And sometimes something I also
like to do is to use sub agents to go
into our current app as the example
and get all context
you need. This is something that I like
to write this use sub agents because
claude is then going to speed up the
process of finding context. Hit enter.
And now Claude is going to build out a
skill for how to create automations like
this. This will take a couple of
minutes. There we go. Now it's asking
some question like what should the skill
be named? I think mini automation fits
pretty well. Should the skill bundle is
start a template directory? Yes. Where
should it live? Let's do in the personal
skills and then click submit answers.
Because we use plan mode, it's now
asking us if we want to accept this
plan. I think it sounds good. So, let's
accept it. And Claude is now going to
build out this skill for us. And there
we go. After a couple of minutes, this
skill is now built. Something that you
always want to ask is, is this a
standalone skill that doesn't reference
the invoice app? Answer this, please.
The reason for that is that sometimes
Claude likes to reference files, but if
you want it to be its own skill, we
don't want it to reference this folder.
We wanted to include all of the
information in that one skill without
needing any other context. But you can
see it says yes, fully standalone, no
path references to any other skill.
Awesome. Now we have created a
standalone skill. When we write Ctrl C
and then click cloud right here and we
now write mini automation, you can see
we have a skill that's called / mini
automation. Build a mini automation in
XJS form on the front end, a trigger.dev
background task on the back end with
composure for third party
authentications,
etc. blah blah blah blah. And now you
can replicate the automation that we
just created with that front-end form
for anything that you want. and you want
to get a habit out of doing this. So,
anytime you build something that you
think, well, I might build this for
another client in the future, please
make a skill for it. It's going to save
you so much time. And especially if
you're building out a websites and you
want like a couple of different
templates to choose from, building out a
custom website and then making it into a
skill is going to be so valuable for
you. I personally believe that in the
future with these Claude businesses, the
value, the IP is going to be the SOPs
and processes that Claude knows just
like in a regular business. Now, what's
really valuable is all of the documents
that businesses have that explains how
they do things. The value in a Claude
code company like this will be the
processes, the skills that Claude has
access to, the information that you have
given it. So, please make sure to make
those skills. They're going to become
valuable and save you a bunch of time in
the future. Make a habit out of it. It's
one of the most important parts of
running a plot code business like this.
All right. Now, we have gone over how
you build websites for clients, how you
also build automations, and how you can
include AI into that to build agents.
The third thing we're going to cover is
kind of like the next level to that,
which is how do you then build out full
AI systems? How do you take a business
and then automate as many processes that
you can and then deliver that to the
client? That's what we're going to cover
now. A full AI system is basically just
a bunch of automations combined. So just
like the invoicing automation that we
just created, when you provide a full
system, you usually automate maybe like
5 to 10 to 25 depending on depending on
how big the project is. So how do you go
about delivering this? This varies from
agency to agency how you actually do
this. Some agencies just deliver a bunch
of init flows where if the client wants
they can look at the executions of the
end inflows, but the reality is that the
client is never going to do that. So the
client just kind of trusts the agency
that it's set up correctly. But that is
how most agencies use to do it. When we
are building with claw code, we want to
give claude access to everything as
well. So we'll do this a little
differently. We're going to be building
a dashboard for the client so they can
see exactly what's going on, exactly how
many executions, maybe even exactly how
much time these automations have saved
them so far. That also allows us to
provide them with tools like we just
created with the invoicing tool where if
they have some process that requires
like something to trigger it like a form
for example like we just showed you can
put those tools inside of this system as
well. This also allows us to have a
front end where they can see all of this
and then also have a separate backend
where everything is running. And
depending on the size of the project and
the client that you're working with,
sometimes the client wants to run
everything on their own servers. And
this system is great for that because
the front end, the actual visuals and
the back end is all going to be running
as code. And specifically the back end,
we're using trigger.dev exactly like we
did in the previous automation. And
because trigger.dev is open source, it
means that we can host it anywhere. We
can host it on a virtual machine like a
machine that's just in the cloud. We can
host it on the service that they're
already running. If they're using
something like Azure, which is the most
normal one that is like a cloud provider
it's called, or if they're using AWS,
Amazon Web Services, or if they're using
Google Cloud. Having a system like this
means that you can basically deploy it
anywhere you want with a very nice user
experience. Let me be clear from the
start. Sometimes it's overkill building
out a full AI system. Let's say that
you're delivering a project for a client
and all they need is just like one
automation done. What you could do is
literally just provide the tool like we
just did connected to something like a
type form where you don't have your own
front end. This is for bigger projects
where you are auditing the entire
business and then say okay these things
are what we can improve and I'm going to
build this out like this and this and
this and you basically get your custom
dashboard custom app where you have
access to all of this. All right let's
get into how we actually build this. The
first thing we're going to build out is
the structure of what is really going to
be a full app. We're going to have the
front end and this is going to be very
similar to what we already built. It's
going to be next.js as the framework.
It's going to be tailwind CSS for the
design. And then I like to use something
that's called Next O for the
authentication that works well with
Nex.js. And then we're going to use
resend together with Nex off. And recent
was basically the service that we can
use to send emails like magic links. And
this is the most secure and easiest way
to set up a login. That way, you don't
have to manage passwords. You don't have
to manage usernames. All you're doing is
just sending a magic link. Every time
someone wants to log in, they click on
that link and they're in. So, it's
basically like forcing a two-factor
authentication every single time, which
is the most secure thing that you can
do. Then, we have the backend. This is
where all of our automations are running
and we're going to be building that in
trigger.dev. We're going to start by
hosting it on trigger.dev, dev. But just
know later on if you wanted to host the
backend yourself, if you wanted it on
something like a virtual machine or
hosting the backend on the client's
actual servers, then trigger.dev is the
perfect thing to build with because it
allows you to just take the code and
just host it somewhere else as well. And
then because we're building out kind of
like a full app, we also need a
database. For the database, I like to
launch fast. And the fastest way that I
found to launch is by using DB,
which is a database provider. And the
database is where we are basically going
to be storing all of this data. So all
of the invoices for example if we have
an invoice generator all of the clients
information like the email and user
information. And what's worth knowing as
well is that we also going to be hosting
MongoDB in the cloud just to launch
fast. If you at one point wanting to
build this entirely on the client's
platform then you can also do that
because MongoDB also has a community
edition that allows you to self-host it
just like you can with trigger.dev. And
while it's not entirely open source,
their community edition is fine for what
you're building as well. So that is kind
of the stack that we are going to be
using. And don't worry if you don't know
what all these things are yet. After
watching this part of the course, you'll
know exactly how to set up full AI
systems like this. Right, let's get into
it. The first thing we're going to do is
that I'm going to build a new folder
right here. I'm going to call this one,
let's just call it AI system. And then
I'm going to go out of claw and write cd
AI system, which is basically just going
to get me into that folder. and then
write pla. The reason I do this is
because I don't want to give it the
context of all the other things that we
have built as well. We want it to be
completely focused on this right here.
What I'll then do is that I'm going to
write I want to build out a full app
for a client that includes a bunch of
small automations. And then I'm going to
write the only domain
that should be allowed into this app
should be at.shiny
AI domains. The reason we do this is
because if we deliver this for a client,
we want to add some additional security
measures that only emails with their own
domain should be allowed into it. This
is basically just an additional layer of
security. Then I'm going to write the
stack next.js. We want to use next off
for authentication
with no Google login because we don't
need that. We want to be using the magic
links, but again, this is something that
you could add later if you wanted to.
Then we want to use Tailwind CSS recent
for magic links. For the back end, I'm
not going to write yet. I'm going to
write backend. Let's
not create this yet, but I want to use
trigger.dev
at one point. So just create
the structure for it and then for the
database we want to use I'm going
to give it some additional information.
This app will be a dashboard for the
automations they have running.
So keep as much as possible in the front
end, only automations in the back end.
Only automations and processes in the
back end. For database, we're going to
use MongoDB. And then I don't want it to
build anything out yet. I don't want you
to build out any automations
yet. I want you to create the structure
of the app. I want a dashboard like they
land inside a symbol
sidebar where they will
have all of the automations and a
settings tab
where they can log out etc. Please build
this out. Then we're going to use
ultraink. I'm going to put it inside of
plan mode to force it to create the full
plan before it starts building. And then
we are going to hit enter. It's going to
take a little longer now the first time
that we are building it out. But just
like we have done previously with the
automations, what we'll later do is that
we're going to create a skill out of
this. And I'm going to give that skill
to you as well. And then we can
basically build out full AI systems like
this in a single prompt. Which next off
version use the latest one? For
components, we can use shared CN
components. How should the shiny AI
domain restriction work? only allow at
shiny.ai domains MongoDB persistence for
all. Let's use the JWT session tokens
and submit answers. There we go. Now
it's going to plan out this entire
thing. And there we go. Claude has now
written up a plan. I'm also going to
tell it to please use the super powers
skill. And I approve of plan. Again, if
you don't know what the superpower skill
is, superpowers is basically a plugin
that includes a couple of skills for
like writing plans, writing skills,
executing plans. It's basically forcing
Claude to think like a developer, which
is very useful when it's building out a
full app. So now it's going to build out
and scaffold this entire project that
took 13 minutes to build out. Now we
want to click into the folder where we
have created all of this. We want to go
into the local example, copy this, paste
this, and then rename it and just call
it.local
like this. Cool. Now, we need to fill
out all of this information. The first
is the off secret. To create this, we
can use this command right here that it
was so nice to show, which is called
open SSL rand, and then B 6432.
Hit enter. That's going to give us a
random string of letters. We can paste
that in instead of the O secret right
here. Just like this one. Then we have
the next URL. For now, we're just going
to keep that at localhost 3000. And then
we go under API keys. Create an API key.
I'm going to call this one AI system. It
should have full access. Click add. Copy
it. Go back. Paste it in right here. And
then I'm just going to write shiny
portal. That is going to be the sender.
And for the email, I'm going to use this
email that I already set up, which is
just going to be this one. So, it's
going to be no reply at mail.clipip.dev.
This is the domain that I'm just going
to use because I've already set it up
once. And we're using the MongoDB URI.
We get that by going to MongoDB. If you
don't have one already, then create a
user. Create a database and a cluster if
you don't have one already. I'm now
going to click connect, click drivers,
and this gives me this string right
here. What we then also want to do is
that we want to click done right here.
Then go into database and network
access. Click edit. And then we can edit
the password. also generate a secure
password. Copy this and paste it in
right here where it says DB password
just like this. And the triggerdev key
is not set up yet. We're going to set
that up later when we set up the
automations and the back end. Now we can
click update user right here. And now it
should work. The last thing we need to
do is that we need to insert the name of
the database. It's not called shiny
right here. It is called newsify right
here. It's from a pre previous project.
So I'm going to fill this out as well.
Cool. Let's try and run it. So, we need
to go inside of AI system by using cd
and AI system. And then we're going to
write npm rundev to start the dev
server. Hit enter. This is going to open
it up. And you can see it starts on
localost 3000. Let's see what it build
out. We definitely need to work on the
design of this. But let me sign in with
elot@shiny.ai.
Send magic link. There you go. Check
your inbox. Can then go inside of our
inbox. Elbertshiny.ai.
Click sign in. And there we go. Now we
have our dashboard right here that shows
total automations, how many active, how
many drafts, recent activity, nothing
yet. Welcome back. Your automations
dashboard, blah blah blah. And then it
says shiny up here. Then we have an
example automation right here where
we're going to have all of the
automations here on the left side. And
then inside of settings, you can see
you're signed into shiny email and then
you can sign out. Great. This is just
the structure of the dashboard. We
definitely need to make this look a lot
better before we do anything else. The
way we do that is that we use the front
end design skill. I'm going to write
that looks good.
I want to give
our app a makeover.
Use the front end design skill. I want
it in a linear light mode type of vibe.
We should have both light mode and dark
mode. Let's build this out. Thanks.
Ultra think hit it with a plane mode so
it plans out how we should do it and
then hit enter. I like to build the
structure first where it doesn't care at
all about the design first. So it builds
it out the right way and then later we
give it a makeover so it doesn't look
this bad. That will probably take a
couple of minutes to fix. Great. Now we
have something that looks more like
this, which looks good. But I can see we
already have an error right here. So I
can click on this little icon to copy
the error. Go back into claw, paste it
in, and say, "Please fix this.
Thank you." And now it's going to fix
this error right here. It's running a
lint. Go. See if it There we go. The
error disappeared. If we write at
elot@shiny.ai, you can see it says check
your inbox. We can then go to our inbox.
Click sign in. Now it says something
went wrong, which is weird. That's
because I clicked on the one that was 20
minutes ago. You got to click on the
newest one right here. 0 minutes ago.
And there we go. Welcome back. Now it
looks like this. And the light mode.
This looks a lot better. There's some
weird thing going on with the gradient.
What I'll do is that I'm going to take a
screenshot of this and say this title
and other text has a weird gradient.
That is too much. Please fix it. Thanks.
I like this theme a lot better. And now
we have both a light mode and a dark
mode. It fixed this elbow text right
here, but it still does that weird
thing. I'm going to take a screenshot of
it again and say, see how in the sides
it's less bright than in the middle. We
don't want that. Please fix. Also, this
light mode button up here. We probably
don't want that. So, what I'm going to
do is that I'm going to say, "Nice, the
light mode button top right corner.
Please remove that
so we only have it inside of settings.
Looks a bit brighter, but it still has
that weird shadow on the left hand side
right here. Let's try and write on the
sides. There's a weird shadow. Can we
please remove that? Actually, I think
it's because these dots in the
background. They probably would need
this shadow. So, I'm going to write they
should
only have the effect on the background
dots, not on the headlines.
and text and
components, etc. You can see it's doing
it on every single page. Kind of like
dark to the sides, but then in the
middle it's like bright. We want it to
be white everywhere. There we go. Now it
fixed it. So the text is completely
white. I think this looks a lot better.
What we're going to do now is we're
going to install our first app. So I'm
going to write let's install our first
app which will be this invoicing app
that also uses trigger.dev as back end.
I want you to one install this front end
form to our AI system folder and two
create the trigger.dev
back end. We're going to call this the
AI system back end right here inside
this folder that will include the back
end for this automation.
Also make it so we later can add more
tasks. That's what it's called inside of
trigger.dev. Uh so more automations
later. For now, let's add this one. I'm
going to set it to plan mode and write
use sub aents to get all context you
need
and
implement
this automation. So now we're going to
take the invoice app that we just built
previously and we're going to install it
into our AI system. And there we go. Now
you can see inside of our app, the send
invoice automation has now been set up.
And now they have the same form that's
now in this new branding where they can
generate and send an invoice much
faster. And then when you're building
out this AI system, it would consist of,
let's say, five to 10 different
automations that are automating
something. And all the employees would
need access to just this dashboard right
here that would allow them to use the
automations. The next thing I want to do
is to handle the authentication. If it's
not off yet, I want to add a O button to
this right here. For this automation,
we need to handle the O. So please add
if we don't have authentication set up
when we trigger it
that a modal pops up where they can
authenticate. When we created this
standalone automation, we handle the
authentication using the link inside of
the terminal via plot code. But of
course, our clients will not be able to
do that. So we need to add a nice button
where they can just authenticate with
whatever they're using. Cool. I hope you
see the idea of how you can build fully
custom AI systems, how you can make it
domain specific, so only people from
this company can use it, and how you now
have this structure to build anything
that you want inside of here. Your
automations doesn't have to be a form
where then something happens. You can
also set up automations that doesn't
require anyone to do anything where it
just runs on autopilot. Let me show you
how to do that, too. But before we do
that, let's make sure that this actually
works. So, the first thing I'm going to
do is that I'm going to go to
trigger.dev. I'm going to create a new
project that I'm going to call AI
system. Then I want to push this
straight to production. So I am going to
get the API key right here, the secret
key. Paste that into environmental value
right here. And we also need to do that
right here. Then we need to go down and
we need to get inside of general the
project ref. So I'm going to insert that
here too. Close this down like that.
Just like before, we need to set the
environmental variable. So I'm going to
go inside of here, click add new, and
then go inside of our environmental
file. Copy all of this and then paste
this into the production like this and
click save. And now I'm going to wait
for it to set up the connection so
everything works and then we're going to
test it. Cool. Let's try and push this
to production. Going to give it the
project ref right here. I'm going to say
we need to set up the back end. I have
installed
all the nontrigger.dev.
This is the project ref. Can you please
set this up?
So, it works with everything,
authentication,
etc. Thank you. So, now we're basically
just going to push this backend code
right here, which is the AI system back
end. We're going to take these tasks
that are the trigger.dev tasks. We're
going to push it to this new trigger.
That we just set up. So, we have
everything in one place. You can see
there's no tasks inside of here yet. And
there we go. I now deployed it to
production. Now you can see the task is
inside of our AI system on trigger.dev
in the production. If I then just make a
test, we can call it Elbert test.
Company name BMA. Just write consulting.
Set it to $1,500
and click generate and send. You can see
it says there we go. Cute run ID run
like this. And now if you go inside of
runs, you can see it's now executing.
And you can see invoice from shiny. Here
we have it. Cool. So now our send
invoice is working. What I'll do now,
just like I explained before, is that
now we have the start, right? This is a
good starting point for every new client
that you get on as well. This overview
dashboard where you have a company name
and one automation is the perfect
starting point for every new client that
you sign on as well. So we want to give
Claude this information. What I'll do is
I'm simply just going to create a new
session. Then I'm going to use the
create skill and I'm going to drag these
in
and I'm going to write I want to create
a skill that creates this kind of front
end
and backend system to when I close a new
client. It should be a generic skill.
So first it should ask what the client
name is, what the domain is
for their emails, etc. It should gather
all of the context first. Then I wanted
to build out this template with the
front end and back end first. After we
have built out this structure, we should
not have any automations yet, we will
then later build automations.
But the entire structure should be
there. So it's very easy to do. This
skill should work stand alone. Should
not reference these folders.
It should have everything included
with references etc
inside its own scope. I'm going to give
it an ultra think and hit enter.
Actually before I do that I'm going to
write use sub agents to gather all the
context for how this works. Thank you.
I'm also going to write include
everything
like design, how it works,
uh domain, the ST, etc. Use sub engine
to gather all the context for how this
works. Thank you. There we go. Bit of a
long prompt, but we're going to use the
create skill now. And again, this skill
is inside the Claude skills folder,
which is inside the free community. So
to get this skill, just go inside of
classroom, go inside of learning hub and
inside of claw skills. Right here, you
have all of my claude skills in this
drive folder and it's completely free to
get. There we go. Now it's going to
start building out this and it's calling
it new client system skill. This will
probably take some time because it needs
to gather all of the context first and
then build the skill. But you really
want to learn how to do this because
every time you build something new for a
client that potentially could be
replicated in the future, you want to
build a skill around it. If you don't do
this, you're going to start from
scratch. Every time you land a new
client, when you do this, you're going
to make your life much easier. And there
we go. Now you can see the skill is
ready. If I go into a new cla session,
just restart cla right quick. And we
then write new client system like this.
It says scaffold new clients full stack
next.js 16 frontend dashboard
trigger.dev bag and worker from the
shiny automations template. Use when the
user says new client onboarded client
scaffold new client system, etc. And of
course, I'm also going to drop this
skill together with the rest of the
skills inside of the Google Drive. Now
you know how to create full agent
dashboard. And you can of course
customize this to however you want. If
you want graphs right here showing you
the task, you can ask Claude to build
it. If you want to add a specific
automation, you can ask Claude to build
it. If you want to add something inside
of settings where they can add the users
themselves, you can tell Claude to build
it. But what I want to do now is build
some more automations inside of this
dashboard to show you how that would
look as well. Let's get into it. All
right, let me show you how to build out
some more automations inside of our own
automation system. And what I'll write
is I'm going to take this folder and
this folder right here which is
basically all the files that this system
includes and then I'm going to write
read how this works. Use sub agents
and then I'm going to say specifically
look at how the automations are created
etc. Then return to me. We just want to
give the context for how this AI system
works before we then try and build out a
new automation inside of this session.
So it'll probably take a couple of
minutes. All right. So let's automate
some more business processes. Let's say
the onboarding for example. A lot of
businesses right now they do manual
onboarding. So they send out emails
manually. They send out the contract
manually. They do all of this stuff
manually. We can create an automation
for this as well and display it inside
of here. So we can now write I want to
create a new automation that is called
start onboarding. This should let's
write up what it should do. Send over
contract via Gmail using Composure of
course. Send another email with a
Calendarly link where they can book an
onboarding call. Send an email with an
onboarding
survey for example. Send another email
with Kenned link. So the connection we
need
is probably just Gmail. The user will
provide
onboarding
link and kell link because it already
now knows the structure of our system.
This should be extremely easy to set up.
I'm also going to write please add this
task to trigger.dev of course like the
other ones straight to prod. And there
we go. Now it's going to build out this
automation just like the other one.
There we go. That was extremely fast. We
can actually see that building out this
automation actually took only 3 minutes
and it was also a pretty simple
automation. But we're going to start
here before we build something a little
more advanced. But let's say that we
just closed me. This is my email. This
is my company. Then we can say send a
contract URL. This could be something
like a docu sign. But we might want to
change this to an actual PDF. So maybe
let's do that. Let's copy this and say,
can we instead here
upload a PDF
on the new tool.
Thank you. Then it's going to change the
automation to do that. Then we insert
the onboarding survey and then the
calendarly URL. So the calendar URL
could be something like this. The
onboarding survey URL be something like
this. And then we need the contract URL,
but that's going to change. Now we can
instead upload a PDF. But I actually
want to generate the PDF instead. Can we
actually instead generate that PDF? For
now, we just generate a dummy contract.
But when we generate, we insert the
actual name and business information,
etc. Please update. And again, if the
client comes back and says, well, I want
this change or can we do this instead?
Then you have everything in code. B can
literally change anything inside of
here. So, it's fully customizable. There
we go. Now, we don't have a field to
upload the contract, but now it's
basically just going to send out a dummy
one. So, let's test if it works. I've
got a shiny
AI BMA. Insert our onboarding survey.
Insert our calendarly form.
Send this in. Click start onboarding.
There we go. You can see it cued this
run right here. If you go into
trigger.dev and look at runs, we can now
see that it's now executing this run.
There we go. It took 12 seconds. Let's
see if I received something in my email.
Now I get the book your onboarding call,
onboarding survey, and your contract.
Let's get started. This is all
automatically sent. You can see we even
generated this draft or placeholder
contract that we can always change later
to exactly what we want. But now it
sends out this contract as well that
includes my information. Absolutely
insane. We just automated the onboarding
process as well. And if the client says,
well, we want a new lead updated inside
of our CRM or we want something else
done. literally just tell Claw to build
it and it's going to build it out for
you. But let's build out some more
advanced automations. Let's get into it.
All right, now you know the basics of
creating these automations. But let's
say that we want to build something a
little more impressive. And this is
usually also the things that you'll be
selling to clients. For example, let's
imagine that a client that you're
working with, they have five support
reps that are answering emails all day
long. And you want to automate, let's
say, our goal is 60% of that. So all of
the questions that are the ones that are
asked all the time that an AI can
literally just answer those questions
almost instantly. We can also build a
full AI agent system like this inside of
our dashboards. The great thing about
this is that it is custom code. It means
that there are literally no boundaries.
We can build whatever we want. So I'm
going to go back into cloud code. I'm
again going to tell it to read the
structure of this full AI system.
then return back to me. Use sub agents.
Understand how it works. Hit enter. It
will gather all of the context that it
needs and then it's going to come right
back. Great. It returns back after 2
minutes and has all the context. Then we
can write, I want to build another
more advanced automation. This should be
a full AI support email ticket response
system
that can respond to around 60% of all
emails. In this
automation, I want the front end to show
the AI responses. I want it to show if
any has been escalated. I want to be
able to upload a full knowledge base. So
it should use rag to search through it
and answer questions based on this
knowledge base. It's getting a little
more advanced here, but luckily we do
have claw that can build out all of this
for us. We will use composio to answer
the emails uh using Gmail. I want to
trigger the trigger.dev dev every 10
minutes to check for new emails and then
respond to every single one that has
come in. If
the ticket requires
human attention, we should be able to
escalate it
and see the escalated emails in the
front end and be able
to respond to them from within the front
end as well. I also want to be able to
see the AI responses inside the front
end, too. Let's see if there's anything
else that we need. Let's plan this
out. Please use the superpower skill and
ask me if you have any questions. Let's
fire away that prompt. And you can see
it's going to load the superpower skill
and ask us any questions if it needs
more context. We can all of a sudden
start building some really cool advanced
stuff based on the current structure
that we have. How should the AI reply
behave for the 60% it's confident about?
It should also send immediately. Of
course, if you're building this out for
a client, you would of course have
talked with the client and asked how it
should do it, but we're going to want to
send immediately. What format will the
knowledge base come in? Let's do let's
do PDF files. Let's actually just do
text files. That is a lot easier. Well,
we can actually turn on all of them.
Submit the answers. Where should we
store the vector embeddings for rag?
We could use something like pine cone or
postgress, but we actually already have
vector search inside of MongoDB. So,
let's use that. Let's do if any human
asks for like low confidence from AI,
angry tone and refund. And let's also do
specific clarifiers like this. Submit.
You can see it's asking all of the right
questions that it needs in order to
build out this plan. Which email account
does this monitor reply from? One shared
inbox. Yes. And there we go. Now you can
see it's exploring the project to get
context. And then it's going to ask a
couple of clarifying questions, come
with a a couple of approaches, and then
design the plan for building this out.
How should we identify a ticket? What
groups emails together? A Gmail thread
is one ticket. That sounds good. When
you escalate and reply from the front
end, should the AI help draft the human
reply? Yep. If we can get AI to
pre-draft the reply, but just not send.
I think that could be pretty cool. Where
do we store tickets, messages, KB
chunks, and embeddings? Reuse existing
MongoDB? Let's do that. Anything
important I should add to the spec pick
anything that apply per ticket tags
labels analytics view could do an
analytics view and a pair ticket tag
submit this submit the answers got it
and after design let me present it in
sections confirm my section one this is
this that sounds good then it's going to
use triggerdev to poll every single 10
minutes this also looks good there we go
that was all of the sections and now
it's saying writing out the spec docs
now that's probably going to take a
couple of minutes. Now we have the full
design spec, which looks good. So I'm
going to tell it to continue. Now it's
going to use this design spec to build
out the entire plan so it can build this
out. It's going to ask us if you want to
use sub agent driven or inline
execution. We definitely want to use sub
agent to speed it up. This means that
different agents are going to be working
on different tasks. You can see I
dispatch a fresh sub agent per task
review between task fast iteration
usually the fastest and also what's
recommended in this superpower skill. So
now it's going to use the sub aent
driven development loaded this
superpower skill and now it's going to
build out this entire thing for us based
on our instructions. This will probably
take a bit to build out cuz it is a
pretty extensive AI system that we are
building out. There we go. The next
thing we need to do is that we need to
go in and get our MongoDB secret. this
one right here. Then we need to go to
our production trigger.dev. Go inside of
environmental variables. Click add new.
Click on production. Make sure that we
have added both the MongoDB URI and the
DB name. Click save. And there we go.
Now I'm going to write we need this to
update on prod trigger.dev.
So it will work.
Can we please do that? Hit enter. And
now it's going to push the changes it
has made to our back end. It's going to
push those trigger.dev so everything
will run smoothly. All right, there we
go. If I now spin up the server, you can
see on localhost 3000, we now have
another automation that's called AI
support. And here we have a couple of
tabs for escalated support request, AI
replied, human applied, and all. We also
have this analytics tab right here that
shows us how many tickets we have. And
we have this knowledge base tab where we
can either paste text into the knowledge
base. We can add PDFs or URLs. Let's see
if this actually works. I can take our
shiny.ai website for example. Paste this
in. Click add to knowledge base. It is
processing now. Let's see if it actually
works. It says error though. So this
didn't work for some reason. Let's try
and see if we can fix this. I tried to
add knowledge base
ran into this issue. Can we check what
happened? In the meantime, let's try and
check the other things like paste text.
So, if I just like copy this entire page
and paste it in right here, add to
knowledge space and call it basic info.
Let's see if it wants to add this. But
then give it a refresh again. Still says
failed. So, there's obviously something
wrong with the knowledge base, but cloud
should of course be able to fix this.
Ah, now I see why it fails. We need an
OpenAI API key. So, I'm going to set
this value as well inside our
environmental value right here at the
end. OpenAI API key. And then I'm going
to go to platform.opi.com.
Log in with my Google account. Let's
just call it AI system. Create the
secret key. Copy it. Paste it in right
here. And then we also need to go into
trigger.dev inside of the environmental
v variables here. Click add new. And add
it here too. Let's do a refresh of this
right here. Go to support. We actually
getting emails now. That is escalated to
us. No emails has been replied to yet.
Let's try and add the knowledge base
once again. probably our entire website
right here. Paste it in. Call it basic
info. Add to knowledge base. Now it is
processing. We refresh. Still processing
now. So it didn't fail instantly. That's
good. Let's delete these others while we
are at it. And there we go. Now it says
ready. So if we go back to inbox, we can
see it has no subject line right now. So
I'm going to copy this and I'm going to
paste this in and say that seems to
work. Issue now is that the subject
lines don't show even though we do have
subject lines.
Can you fix please hit enter and then
hopefully it can fix this subject line
not showing but this is an actual email
from my inbox which is kind of cool.
Same with this one. This is also an
actual email. So it's actually fetching
the emails which is kind of cool. And it
is escalating them. Great. I think I
also want to add a refresh button
somewhere on this page. So, I'm going to
give it this page right here and say,
can we add a refresh button here as well
that triggers
a polling, please? That way, we can also
do it manually just to get all the
newest ones. And there we have it. Now,
we have a little poll inbox button right
here. If we pull it, it says refreshing
just like this. And then it shows us if
we have any new emails in our inbox. So,
let's actually try it. Let me go on this
email account right here. Right to my
personal email right here. Basically
write what does shiny AI do? We can
basically just ask, hi, saw your
website. What is it that Shiny AI does?
We can click send. And now I receive my
email inside of my inbox. Let's see if
we also receive it. If we hit a little
polling right here, for some reason it
doesn't show. Maybe it's because it's
under AI replied. Hm.
Check the latest poll.
I ran it after sending an email to
myself to check it, but
the email doesn't show up.
Why is that? Check the latest logs.
Let's see if I can figure out what
happened. There we go. The issue was
apparently that I clicked in on it, so
it became red. Of course, we only want
to take the unread emails. So yeah, the
system is actually working like it's
intended. Cool. But it's still being
escalated. So we need to fix some
prompting. I think I can write see this
email.
It's a simple question and we have it in
our knowledge base.
Why did it get escalated?
Hit enter and see what it says. All
right. This was another one of these
issue where it wasn't really an issue. I
just had to refresh. But now I've added
auto refreshes every 30 seconds inside
of this tab. And if we go to AI replied
and we click in on this, we can actually
see, hey, saw your website blah blah
blah. And then the AI actually replied
with this. Hi, thanks for reaching out.
China AI helps businesses boo sales.
It's using the information that it got
from the website. And if we click why
this reply, we can even see the
confidence score of how smart it thinks
it was. We can see the citations that it
used from our knowledge base. This is
extremely cool and it works. So now we
basically have an AI inside of our
support email that can reply to
questions. When this confidence score
isn't as high, it's going to put it in
the escalator tab so we can reply to it.
I hope you start to see the power of
these insane automations and agent
systems that you can all build inside of
your own kind of dashboard right here
and provide to a client. And the great
thing is that as you build these systems
out, you could then sell this support
inbox to another client and it wouldn't
really take you that much work to set it
up with a new knowledge base on a new
client. And the crazy thing is the
amount that you could sell this for. If
you sold this to a big company, you
could probably charge anywhere from $2
to $5,000 a month depending on how big
the team is. Cuz think about it, right
now their support rep is probably being
paid maybe like $2,000 a month. If it's
in the US, then probably three to $4,000
a month. So if a team has, let's say, 10
support reps and all of a sudden they
only need five, you're saving them five
times, let's say, $3,000, that's $15,000
a month you're saving them. And if
you're charging $5,000, you're still
saving them $10,000 a month. And this is
just one of the automation systems that
you can build out. You can automate all
processes inside of a business. Smack
all of these automations here on the
left hand side, and you have a killer
product. And you can manage all of this
with plot code. What I'll do is that I
will take the code for this entire
dashboard right here with the trigger.
Backend. So these folders right here, AI
system and AI system back end. I'm also
going to take the cityscape website. So
you have that as well as reference. And
I'm going to put the GitHub repost right
below this video. The last thing I want
to do is that I want to host the front
end. Right now we are still on localhost
3000. The back end is hosted on the
cloud.trigger.dev,
but the front end isn't hosted yet. And
it's honestly quite easy to do. It's the
exact same thing we did with the other
website. We just open visil.com and
click add new project. Then we want to
push this to GitHub. So I'm going to say
I want to push only the front end. So
that only this AI system folder right
here. That's the front end, not the back
end, only the front end to GitHub.
Then we're going to open a new tab.
We're going to go to github.com. We're
going to create a new repo. I'm going to
call it AI system front end. We're going
to make this private. Create repository.
Then we can copy the link right here. We
can paste it in and say push to this
repo. You won't be able to do this in
auto mode. So I'm going to set it to
just like the default mode. Hit enter.
And then we will have to accept the
commands. It's asking us what to push.
I'm going to ask it. I want to push this
to separate repo so I can host the front
end. So only the AI system standard push
it's it's empty brand new and then we
push it. Something that I always like to
do is that I write of course don't push
any secrets
etc. Just so we don't push any of these
secrets to GitHub for security. Always
good to remind Claude not to do that.
Sometimes it gets ahead of itself. It is
running all of these commands. We'll
just let it do that. There we go.
Created a little mini plan for itself.
Now it's going to push this frontend
repo to GitHub. There we go. Now it is
pushed. If we go onto GitHub, then hit
enter. Now you can see we have all of
the files inside of here. Let's host
that by going to VIL, copying this
GitHub repo, pasting it in, clicking
deploy. It's going to see that it's a
NextJS application right here, click
deploy again, and let's see if we have
any build errors. See, we already have a
build error. So what I'll do is that I'm
going to copy this. Better thing to do
actually is to go inside of here where
we are running it. And then in instead
of npm rundev, we can write npm run
build which is going to show us all of
the build errors inside of this folder.
You see it compiles successfully running
typescript. This actually built
successfully. So I'm not sure what this
error is. So let's copy this, paste it
in and say when I try and host on this I
get this.
Why the front end installed MongoDB7 but
PNA installed both the cell doesn't pass
legacies by default to clean fixes are
dark mango6. Let's do what it
recommends. There we go. It pushed the
changes to GitHub. So let's try and
deploy it again. We can just click
deploy once more. And now we should not
get this error again. You can see it
passed the first 10 seconds which was
where we had an error before. And there
we go. Congratulations. You now deployed
a project. Let's continue to dashboard.
we get this domain right here that we
can go to and you can see this will now
be the login screen right here which
will only allow us to sign in with a
shiny domain. So I'm going to write my
email, click send magic link and we see
something went wrong which is because we
don't have our environmental var
variables yet. So go inside of here and
then we need to fill out all of the
environmental variables. Click add
pasting in all of these. Click save and
do a little redeploy like this. This
will take another minute or so and then
it will deploy it. Let's click right
here. View deployment. Look at logs
right here. Build logs to see if it
deploys like it should. There we go.
Build completed. If we then give it a
refresh and write in our email. Now it
should work. I can see right here that
it's going to local host. And that's
because I forgot to change one of the
environmental variables. So let's go to
next or UL right here. You can see we're
going to be using this UL instead.
Pasted this in. Click save and click
redeploy. Right now we're using this
domain right here which is the domain
that VIL gives us. But you probably want
to add your own domain when you set up
an AI system like this. The way you do
that is that you just go inside of a
cell again go down to domains and then
just click add existing and you can
write in whatever domain you want and
connect it using DNS. If you have any
issues with that then you can just ask
claude. After you've changed the domain,
then it's very important that you go
inside of the environmental variables
just like I forgot to do now and change
this next off URL to be the URL where
your app is running. If you don't do
that, you're going to run into the same
issue that we just did before. Now it's
deployed once again. Let's hit enter.
Write in elot shiny.ai. Now it is
sending the magic of URL. And now we are
in and we have our AI support. We have
our AI send invoice. We have our start
onboarding. We have all of the processes
that we built just before. There we go.
Now you have deployed an AI system that
could be for a client. Congratulations
for reaching this far into the course.
Great. Now you know how to build in
these three levels. Websites as the
easiest thing to build, then individual
automations to automate stuff with
trigger.dev, dev and then how you can
build a full app and dashboard around it
that has multiple different automations
in order to deliver a full project. What
I'll show you next is my structure and
my way of basically being able to build
anything cuz now you know a couple of
things you can build and deliver to a
client. But if a client has some
specific request and you want to build
something that you don't have a tutorial
on that doesn't exist on YouTube, how do
you go about that? How do you build
anything? I usually break it down into
four different steps. The first thing
before I even start building anything,
we need to create a really really good
build plan. This includes things like
the tick stack that we are using, how it
will work, what database, what
frameworks, what exactly is it that we
are building. It also includes things
like the design, how should it look,
what should the feel of the thing we are
building, what should that be like? And
that is actually the most important step
of building anything. And the reason for
that is that there are so many things
that goes into this step of figuring out
okay what are we building and how do we
build it specifically with the tech
stack because if you're building
something like an app or an automation
the text stack is what determines what
the cost of running it will be and how
fast it's going to be as well and how
well does it scale and if we at one
point later on wants to add more things
is that possible can we add more
features can actually do the things that
we want can we give it the functionality
that we need and want in our app or
automation or whatever it is that we are
building this build plan what most
beginners do when they're building
something is that they just write I want
to build this and this and this hit
enter and then take it from there but
what happens most of the time is that
they end up with a bad text stack they
don't go back and forth with the large
language model in order to actually get
the best text stack possible for what
they're trying to do and they end up
launching something that is mediocre
that makes them run into issues later
down the line when it comes to scaling
the cost, how fast there is
functionality, etc. So before we start
building anything, we want to have the
text stack dialed. We want to keep going
back and forth with Claude until we get
the best text stack possible. And then
we also want to nail the design so we
know exactly what the feel should be of
the user experience before we even start
building anything. It's much harder down
the line to change something from bad to
good rather than just building it from
good in the start. After we have done
that, after we have spent a lot of time,
and I'm literally talking hours here, if
you're building something complex,
figuring out the tech stack, figuring
out the design, and making sure that all
of these will be good, now it's time to
build out the implementation plan. What
people that are a bit more intermediate,
but still beginners, what they do is
that they maybe just make one plan of,
okay, this is what I want to build, give
it to Claude, and then have that build
it out. and port will actually do this
next step itself which is building out
an implementation plan. But you're going
to get much better results if you
actually verify that you have a good
implementation plan. An implementation
plan is basically a plan for how do you
actually build the thing that you have
written out in the build plan. And the
way I like to do them is split them up
in steps. And for each step I want a
bunch of different checkboxes. So to
give you an example, step one might be
to set up file structure. And in the
file structure, there's a bunch of
different subst steps in setting up the
file structure and you want to write all
of this out in your implementation plan.
And if you're building something very
complex, you might have something like
40 steps in your implementation plan in
order to build the thing out that you
want. And before you even start building
anything, you want to make sure that you
have this implementation plan dialed. In
step two, the next thing we might want
to build out is maybe the database
structure and then maybe authentication.
Cloud knows the best sequence of how to
build out anything, but you want to
force it to make a good implementation
plan. You want to force the AI to really
make a decision and make a good decision
for how to build out the thing that you
want. And then after you've made the
build plan and you've made a good
implementation plan, that is when you
start building. And the way you do that
now is that you give the large language
model this implementation plan of
course. And then you tell it, please
start with step one. And the large
language model is now going to start
with this substep, then do this substep,
and then do this substep, and come back
to you and say, well, step one has now
been complete. Do you want me to start
with step two? And then it's going to
start step two. It's going to do the
substeps inside of step two, and then
it's going to finish. This is much
better than just giving it an entire
plan or just giving a build plan and
letting it control everything itself. By
this you force it to do it in the best
sequence possible and you have planned
everything out before you even start
building anything. I hope you start to
see the power of building out both a
build plan and an implementation plan.
And actually when it comes to like the
time that you're building, step one and
two will be where you spend 80% of your
time. Step three when building something
out. And actually building it will only
take around 20% of the time. A lot of
people in the AI space get this wrong
and they spend 80% of the time just
letting the LLM build and only 20% of
the time planning it out if they even do
plan it out at all. So when you made a
build plan, you made an implementation
plan and the AI has gone through every
single step all the way down to step 40
or however long your implementation plan
is and the AI is not done building it,
then it's finished and you'll have to
test and refine it a lot. You'll
definitely run into bugs. that almost
always happens and you basically just go
through them, paste the bug to plot and
have it finish everything. That is
basically how you go about building
something. In all of this, you want plot
to be almost a consultant that can
explain to you what is the best text
stack. What should I use for building
this? What gives me the best results?
And a bonus tip that gives you even
better results is if you use two large
language models. It could either be two
clawed code sessions, could also be one
clawed and then one codeex. But if you
have one AI as kind of like the
consultant that decides what to use and
then you take that decision and you give
it to another AI model and you say, "Is
this true?" They're then going to bounce
ideas and make sure you get the best
result possible. And by doing that, you
can start with absolutely no technical
ability and you can figure everything
out on the fly. Awesome. Let me actually
demonstrate exactly how you do this by
building something that I have no idea
how to build. And I'll show you exactly
how you use this four-step framework
right here to do the exact thing that we
just talked about. Let's get into it. To
show you that this actually works and to
show you how to actually do it, let's
build something that I haven't built
before just to show you that it actually
works and that you can build something
really, really good without knowing how
it works. First, I want to build a lead
enricher. What that basically means is
that I want to be able to insert a name
or an email or a LinkedIn URL and from
that I want to search up a database of
some kind of sort and from that I want a
software that can go out and get all
information on that person. So if I
wanted to find someone's email, I could
just paste in their LinkedIn URL and
that would give them their email. I have
a slight idea of how to build this. I
can probably use some API from like
Apollo or something, but I wanted to
show you how you can know none of that
and get all the answers from Claude in
order to build it out. So, I'm not going
to help it and tell it what to do.
Claude is going to make the decisions
for us. I have a blank project right
here. I'm just going to head under the
terminal and click new terminal and then
open up a Claude session right here and
click yes, I trust the author. Then
going to drag it on top right here. And
I'm going to write I want to build a
lead in richer.
First I want to build a
build plan. Ask me some questions about
how it should work. So we can create a
bill plan as amp file. We just set it to
auto mode and hit enter. And now Claude
will ask us a couple of questions to
basically build the thing that we want
to build. And you can actually see it's
even using the superpower skill which
kind of forces this entire process. This
superpower skill first creates the build
plan of what we want to build which is
basically what it calls a design spec
and then it actually also builds out an
implementation plan. This is what's
going on under the hook for the
superpower scope. You can see it says
what's the input to the lead enricher?
What do you start with? I want to be
able to start with anything
and from that.
So either email
company domain
name plus company
LinkedIn
URL and from that get all of the
information. So, I should
be able to
insert what I have. Hit enter. What
output fields do you want the enricher
to return for each lead?
Let's do person basics and contact info
and company info. And then, yeah, let's
get socials as well. Submit.
Hit enter. Which enrichment data source
do you want to use? This is where we
want to make sure that we actually make
a good decision. Choosing an enricher is
the biggest cost of running this. And
right here, it's giving an option to
have multiple and use each as fallback.
I like that idea. So, let's do that.
What do you want to interact with in
Richer? Let's do a small web app like
this. How should leads be input into the
web app? Both single bulk one form from
a single lead. Let's just do single lead
only for now. Do you want to store
enrich leads or is it lookup only? Store
history. And if you reach a question
where you don't know the answer, you can
literally just scroll down. If you're
using the superpowers plugin, you can
also just go out of it and then discuss
it with Claude. But we can write chat
about this and then say, what would you
recommend? And then it says, I recommend
store history in a database. Reasons
saving on cost blah blah blah. The only
reason to skip storage is if you have a
strict privacy policy compliance reason.
Let me just say for now that we don't
need to store it. Now you can see it
says got it. Look up only. How should
the provider fall back chain work when
enriching a lead sequential with merge?
Try Apollo first, then Hunter. Let's try
and just say let's just try Hunter
first.
And I want it to stop when it finds the
email
cuz that is the main thing. If there's
something that you don't understand,
something that you don't have an answer
to that you think is best, you should
just ask cloud what it would recommend.
Here you can see it says what order
should the providers be tried in gives
us a couple of options. I'm just going
to say hunter only, but you can l just
go back and forth with claude like this.
What's the text stack? Should I match
the shiny automations template? It knows
this from memory. Um, let's do next year
only and no trigger.dev for now. I have
enough to draft the design. Here's the
proposal architecture blah blah blah.
That's all of this. And now it's
creating what's called the design spec.
And the design spec is basically what I
called the build plan in my previous
explanation of how to build anything.
You can see it has two questions, two
things I like to decide before I write
the spec. How should I handle the
LinkedIn in URL case? Let's for now skip
skip and let's do a drop down. The skill
I'm using right here, which is also very
valuable for you to know about, is
called superpowers. And what superpowers
basically does is that it forces Claw to
think like an engineer. All you have to
do is literally just search GitHub
superpowers. You're going to find this
GitHub repo right here. It's called Opra
Superpowers. Click on this and you can
see it has 28,000
stars. All you do is that you literally
just copy this right here and you go to
claw and you say, "Please install these
skills. search up the documentation for
installing global claw skills before you
do it.
You just send this like this and it's
going to install the skills for you.
After you've done that, you might have
to restart claw just like this before
it's ready. But now you can see spec
written and saved to ducks superpowers.
And then it has the spec right here. And
that is sign. There we go. So if we
click this, you can now see it build out
a full plan for us. And we want to read
this carefully to make sure that aligns
with exactly what we want to build. So
you can see it says lead enricher design
spec. It shows the date. It shows the
status which is draft a goal a personal
web tool for enriching a single lead at
a time. The user enters whatever they
have email company name or domain name
and domain name and company. And the app
returns the lead's contact information
company info and social presence. There
we go. Non goals. We don't need a CSV
enrichment. This is not what we want. It
shows the stack right here. It shows the
user flow. shows the architecture, shows
the component responsibilities, what
each page should do. You can basically
see we have a full plan already for
exactly what it is we want to build. If
we find something inside of here that we
don't like, we can tell CL to fix it in
the implementation plan. It even shows
how the enrich lead should be
structured. It shows error handling. It
shows file layout and it shows out of
the scope maybe for the future. Like
this. Nice. Now we have our full build
plan. And right now we're building a
fairly simple tool. is just like a
personal tool. If you were to build out
a full software for example, then this
would definitely be an extremely long
build plan. You would have to include
pricing and authentication and databases
and maybe you're running some virtual
machine or like hosting the back end.
All of this would be inside of your
build plan or what superpowers call it
the design spec. You see it says spec
written and saved. I'll say I have read
it now. Please continue. Now you can see
it's using a different skill also coming
from superpowers that's called writing
plans. And this is where we go to the
next step which is building out the
implementation plan with these substeps.
And building out this implementation
plan is actually the thing that usually
takes the longest. I'll let it do that
and then I'll come right back. And there
we go. Now you can see the plan is
complete and saved inside of plans. And
this is what the implementation plan is.
Right? If we click on plans and I'll
click on this, you can see we have the
entire file structure. We have task one,
do this and this and this and this. Set
all of these things. Step five, step
six. So it's basically split up in tasks
and then steps inside of these tasks
exactly like this. So now we have two
options. Do we want sub aent driven
where each thing are built where a fresh
sub agent is doing each task? This
speeds it up a lot. or do we want to do
everything in line? I'm going to do one
sub agents.
Start the build and only now after we've
made a spec and after we've made a plan
is when we start building it out. So now
it's going to build out this little mini
app for us which is a lead enricher. And
there we have it. Now Claude has built
out this entire thing by following the
implementation plan. And this took 13
minutes. The next thing we want to do is
testing and refining. And we are
probably going to run into some bugs. So
you can see we have our environmental
values right here. Let me copy that,
paste it, and then rename it to just
local. And let's then update this Hunter
API key. Go to hun.io and go to API.
Copy this API key. Go back. Paste it in
right here. Close it down. And let's try
and run the server. So we can now write
npm rundev. That's going to give us
localhost 3000. Paste it in and let's
see if our app works. So it says lead
enricher right here. What do you have?
Let's say we have a name and company and
the name we can write this. Let's test
it on myself first. Company name
shiny.ai.
Let's see if we can find it using this.
Click enrich. Now we run into this issue
right here. So I'm going to copy this.
This was as expected. Paste it in and
say we run into this issue. Hit enter.
And then we should be able to fix it. It
was something to do with how it's
passing the information. So let's see if
it works now. So you can see it's making
a bunch of updates now in the code. Now
it wants to test it. We can just stop it
here. Let's try and restart the server.
Write name and company email again.
Click enrich. And there we go. Now we
have a bunch of information. And it
could even just from my name and the
company name, it could find my email.
Let's see if I just write shiny.ai and
click enrich. See what data it then
finds. Then you can see it actually
finds Oliver, my co-founder, and his
email. And there we go. The lead
enricher works. It's not a very
impressive app because it literally just
uses the Hunter API. But it was also
show you this flow right here of
building something that you've never
built before by using these four steps.
Creating the build plan, creating the
implementation plan, and then having the
LLM build for you, but spending a lot of
time on the build plan and the
implementation plan. And then when you
have all of that, when you have
sharpened your X, that's when you start
building it. And I guess we can do the
next step, which is testing it and
refining it. We have already done a bit
of bit of testing, but let's refine it
as well. I can give it the front end
skill now and say make it look clean and
modern like a modern says.
Hit enter. And now it's basically just
going to give our entire software a full
makeover of how it looks. That's a part
of the refining step. Actually making it
look good. There we go. Now we have
given it a bit of a makeover. Now find
anyone's work email. And now we can
choose either email, domain, name,
company. works exactly like it did
before, but now it just looks a little
better. Awesome. The reason I wanted to
build this out is just to showcase how
you basically build anything. So, when a
client comes to you and tells you, I
want to build out this and this and
this, I want to try and automate this.
Is this possible? You can literally just
ask Claude about how would I build this?
How would I go about this? Use this
framework right here for first creating
a build plan, creating the
implementation, and then having it built
out. And that basically allows you to
build anything you really want or would
never need. If you're already technical,
then you might be able to skip some of
these stages. Like you might already say
that I want to use this and this and
this text stack because you already know
that this text stack would be good for
the task. But if you're a beginner and
you're just starting out and you don't
have that much technical expertise,
don't skip the step of just chatting
with Claude and finding out what the
best tech stack would be for things like
scaling, cost, how fast it is, the
functionality, etc. go back and forth
with Claude a lot about that and you're
going to get the best results. In the
next part of the course, we're going to
talk about pricing because now you know
how to create a bunch of stuff. But how
do you actually price it? How much can
you charge? What pricing model should
you use? That is what we're going to
cover now. Now you know how to build a
bunch of different things. And you also
know the framework for basically being
able to build anything using clawed
code. But how do you actually price your
services? How much should you be
charging? This is a question I get a lot
and I always use the golden rule that
when it comes to developing an AI
project, you always want to give your
clients a 5x return on investment. So,
let's say that you save your client
$5,000 in payroll or in whatever
solution that you implemented, you would
be able to charge a $1,000
from that for your service. If you keep
this 5x return on investment, your
client will always be happy. And a happy
client means low churn, which basically
means that they stay with you for a very
long time. If they're paying you
monthly, you of course want them to stay
as long as possible. And it increases
referrals. If you did a good job for
them, then they're going to refer you to
their friends that are also business
owners that might also have the issue
that you're solving. And this is where
you potentially can achieve negative
churn. Which basically means that your
agency grows without you doing anything
just from serving your clients right now
without paying anything else in
marketing. Your agency would still
increase because the churn is so low and
clients are referring you to other
clients in a higher rate than the churn
you have. And that all starts by giving
your clients a good return on
investment. That's the entire point of
this business model and in any service
business really. you need to go in and
do a hell of a job, give them a return
on investment in order to actually
deserve the $1,000. But how do you
actually calculate the return on
investment for your services? It is
basic math. Let's just use an example
that you are installing voice agents and
and right now you're working with a
client that right now has 10 people in
customer support and they are taking
calls all day. They're answering the
same questions over and over again. So
now you installed your voice agent
system and this now means that they go
from 10 customer support reps to let's
say five customer support reps. This
means that they have cut five customer
support reps. Each rep might be paid
something like $2,000 a month. So when
you have cut from 10 down to five, that
is five reps. That basically means that
you're now saving this company $10,000 a
month. So using the 5x return on
investment rule that mean that from that
in order to keep the client very happy
you'll be able to charge $2,000
a month for that. And if you do it like
this then they have no reason to churn.
You're literally saving them still
$8,000 every month just from using your
system. Of course you need to do some
work. You need to maintain it. You need
to make sure that voice agents actually
do a good job. But that is also what
you're paid to do. That is how you can
calculate a return on investment. You
might also have a system that directly
generates revenue. Let's say you have
like a cold email AI system that you
install for clients. And that system is
generating a business, let's say
$100,000 a month in new revenue. When
you do this, you need to calculate in
gross profit because this is revenue.
Gross profit is what you have left after
you remove the fixed cost. So things
like payroll for taking care of the
client. How much is the company actually
profiting from that $10,000 worth of
revenue that might be let's say if they
have good margins like $40,000. So that
is in theory what you're making them
every single month. You can charge one
of that which means if you're running
this system right here you'll be paid
$8,000 a month. So you always want to
give them at least a 5x return of their
money. And of course, this $100,000 a
month in revenue that you're giving them
needs to be new revenue, right? Not
their existing revenue already. So, if
you can by installing your system, give
them a 5x return on investment, then
they're going to be very happy and
they're going to stay with you forever.
But what pricing structure do you then
use? If you want to make it really easy
and if you want to follow the the golden
rule when it's available, when result
based, when it makes sense, is a very,
very good offer. If you literally just
say to them upfront that you're going to
be taking 20% of the gross profit that
you make a company, that is such a
no-brainer because there's no risk in it
for them. You remove all of the risk.
Now there's only an upside and it also
shows that you're very confident in what
you're doing. The negatives are of
course is that you need to be able to
track all of this. So this usually works
with larger clients where you can
actually go in and control and see okay
how much money am I making them that you
can follow each lead in the process that
they have a good CRM etc. That's one of
the really good offers resultbased and
when you are good at what you do
resultbased will also usually pay you
more than something like a regular
retainer. Let me give you an example.
Shiny.ai which is our AI agency does
lead reactivations and we always use
resultbased. We had one client where we
probably could have charged maybe like
$1,000 a month on a retainer, but
because we did it as result based
because we went after the golden rule,
that client in total actually made us
around $240,000
in LTV. So, we probably at least 10x the
lifetime value just from doing it result
based. Resultbased is one of those
offers that you'd rather have a retainer
if you're bad at what you do. But if
you're really really good at what you
do, you would always rather have
resultbased because you're paid for
every result that you bring. So if you
can scale that up, your result also
scales infinitely. I hope that kind of
makes sense. But this offer right here
is not always the best one to use
because sometimes it could be hard to
calculate how much something is worth.
Let's say that you are implementing
customer support widgets on websites,
right? So this little website widget in
the bottom right corner, it's very hard
to say how much a conversation is worth.
You could still do result based. It will
probably not be of gross profit.
Instead, it might be per conversation,
for example, that you're charging them a
little something. Maybe you're charging
them something like $1 per conversation.
So this still definitely still add up if
they have like 200, 300 conversations a
month. But that's one way that you can
do these kind of like support agents as
result based. But you cannot really like
calculate gross profit directly from
like a support agent. So sometimes
resultbased really doesn't make sense.
Instead, what I recommend at that point
is the upfront offer plus recurring
because sometimes it's simply like
impossible to track and it also becomes
a headache if you have like 50 clients
to track their performance every single
month. So charging something up front
and then a recurring afterwards is
sometimes the best option. But if you do
that, I'll always recommend that you use
the satisfaction guarantee. This has
worked so well for us. Let's say that we
want to charge a client $2,000 upfront
and then let's say $500 a month. If we
just give them this offer right here,
there's a bunch of risk, right? The
client is taking a risk. Okay, does this
even work? And they're paying a pretty
big amount right up front without even
seeing if it's going to work yet.
Instead, what I want you to do is to
give a satisfaction guarantee. So, you
still charge $2,000 upfront. You say,
"I'm going to build this out. It's going
to cost $2,000 as a setup fee, but I'm
so confident in my own ability that I
can build this really well out for you."
So, after I build out the entire system,
so if you're building a dashboard, you
will build out everything. If you're if
you're building a website, you'll build
out everything. You're basically going
to say that I'm going to build out
everything so you can see exactly how it
looks. Then we're going to hop on a
meeting and if you don't like the result
at that moment, then you can get a full
refund. So then we have the satisfaction
guarantee. The reason why this is so
strong is because now all of a sudden
there's no risk in it for them. If they
don't like what you have built, then
they can just get their money refunded
right afterwards. But if you're actually
good at what you're doing, which you
hopefully are, then people are not going
to refund because they're going to see a
website that they actually like or
they're going to see a dashboard that
actually automates the things that they
want automated. It's very important
sometimes for some projects that he gets
some money up front. The reason for that
is that it has happened countless of
times for us that we have started the
project without taking any money up
front and then the client simply like
stopped answering. Maybe he got cold
feet, maybe something else came up,
maybe he was just too busy. But the
reason they could just like stop
answering and don't care anymore is
because they were not invested. You want
people to be invested right from the
start when you work with them. So, this
is like the perfect middle ground. You
still get them invested. You still get
money up front, but you remove the risk
by giving them a satisfaction guarantee.
And if you're good at what you're
actually doing, we have given this offer
a bunch of times. And we have never had
to give a refund. Because every single
time we have shown someone a website,
for example, or shown someone a system
that we have built out for them, they
have said, "This looks good. I'm ready
to try it. Awesome. Let's get started."
And for a lot of the time, actually
forget about the satisfaction guarantee
when they see something that's really
good. And then I'm a big fan of
recurring businesses. I don't like to
work on a project basis. I like having
recurring revenue coming in every single
month. So when you charge an upfront fee
and then charge a lower recurring fee,
this lower recurring fee is usually not
a problem. And this really helps when
you start to stack like 10 plus clients,
all of a sudden this recurring revenue
is just stacking and compounding. What
you basically justify is that this is to
keep up support. It's to keep the system
active to fix anything if any issues
come up. That is what this fee basically
like a service fee covers, right? Which
is a monthly recurring fee. Another
thing that's very important to talk
about is that you always of course want
to make sure that you profit. You don't
want to build out a full system for them
and then cover let's say the software
cost yourself and then realize that you
that you're not going to profit. A way
to overcome that is to use tiers just
like you would with the software where
you have like tier one, tier two, tier
three that becomes more and more
expensive. You can do that as well with
your AI services. The key here being
that you always want to make sure that
you profit. Let's say that you're
building out the voice agents to use the
example from before. Then you could
have, let's say, 100 calls on plan one.
Let's say a,000 calls on plan two and
let's say 5,000 plans on plan three. And
then have maybe like a fourth plan
that's like 5,000 plus, which is maybe
per conversation or something that you
can charge for. By doing that, by having
different tiers, you always make sure
that you are in the green. If you're
just charging like 500 bucks a month and
all of a sudden you realize that this
company is massive and they're going to
have like 10,000 calls a month, you
might get ruined. So, you want to make
sure that you're dialed in on this and
that you are always in the profit. A
question I get a lot as well is, should
I include software in my price? Like,
let's say that you're building out the
voice voice agents as an example. it
costs maybe like $100 a month for you to
run it. Should you sell that to the
client and get them to pay $100 extra or
should you include it in your price? So
if before if you're charging 500 bucks,
then it would just charge 600 bucks
without telling them. And from my
experience, what I've seen is that a
confused person doesn't buy. If someone
is confused about what they're going to
pay, what they're going to get, they're
not going to purchase anything. So you
want to make your offer as simple as
possible. Instead of saying, well, it's
like $500 a month for the service and
then a $100 a month for the actual
software, we almost always include it
all in our price and just have a very
simple offer that is easy to understand.
There's one scenario, however, where we
don't do this, but where we actually do
this, and this is if the client wants to
like own the system completely or like
run it on their own servers. This is
usually like bigger clients that wants
to run everything on their own servers.
The price tag for that is of course
going to be much higher as we now need
to install it on their servers. And when
we're doing that, they are of course
also paying for like the hosting and the
software cost. So I'd say when you're
just starting out like 99% of the time
you would just include the cost inside
of your price. When you start going up
market and working with larger clients
that's sometimes when you have to sell
them well it's going to cost this and
this on your own servers and you
basically take the price out of your
service fee. I mentioned it a bit
earlier, but please, this is just like a
reminder. You never say the price of the
service before you have shown the value.
It's what we talked about, right? You
don't, for example, if you're typing
with someone in the DMs over email and
they're going to ask, "How much is it
going to cost?" You never say the price
before you show what you're actually
delivering. You also want to say on the
call that you're trying to give them a
5x return on investment. They need to
see the value that they are going to get
to compare it to the price that they're
going to pay. You want to be judged on
the value, not on the price. And the
only way that you can do that is that
you hop on a call with them. You talk
about the issues that they currently
have and then show them how your
solution could be a solution to their
problem. If you this up, then
you're never going to get them on a call
because they're just going to see, well,
it's $2,000. That's way too much in
debt. But if they realize that it's
actually going to save them $10,000,
then paying that $2,000 is a steal. And
the other thing is that a lot of people
when they start selling in the AI space,
they are selling AI. They're foc
focusing on the features like we are
using the newest models. We're using the
newest technology. We are running it
smooth so it's as fast as possible. The
reality is that most companies that
you're going to work with doesn't really
care that it's AI at all. All they care
about is the outcome that they're going
to get. Will they be able to save
$10,000 a month? Yes or no. They don't
care about if it's AI or what it is
doing it. They just care about the
outcome. So when you are on calls and
you're explaining the value that you
focus on the pain that they have right
now, the amount that they're paying
extra right now, which they don't have
to, and then from that, show them the
outcome. Show them what you can help
with. Don't focus on the features. Don't
focus on it being AI. I hope that
clarified some things in terms of
pricing. Now you have all of the
information that you really need in
order to go out and actually start
selling AI services. If you want my
help, then you should check out our
community, the 1% in AI. Inside of here,
we have the 30-day challenge and the
90-day challenge. And the great thing
about these challenges is that when you
complete them, then you actually get
your first month completely refunded.
The way it works is that you get this
tracker right here that shows you what
to do every single day, what modules to
watch inside of the 1%, what task to
complete, and it basically holds your
hand throughout the entire process of
learning the skills that you need to
learn and setting up your AI agency. So,
if that sounds interesting, then I'll
leave it as the top link right below
this video. Thank you guys so much for
watching. I hope you have a wonderful
rest of your day. I hope that you're
actually going to use this for
something. Don't let this be another
YouTube video that you've just watched
and never actually took action. I am
rooting for you. Good luck.